<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<Topics>
	<Translate NoParse="1">Text</Translate>
	<MaxNumRacesInFile>15</MaxNumRacesInFile>
	<Topic Name="MISC_FIRST_CONTACT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We welcome you to the stars, Human. While it may not seem it by my looks, the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] are a friendly civilization that wish peace and love for all.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hail, Human traveler! The [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] have made claims to many of these worlds.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>So, this is a Human. Your skin looks... delicious. The [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] loves good skin. I am sure in time that we will meet for dinner...#Beware, Humans. Your meddling ways are not appreciated.#Ah, Human. Good to see you up on your hind legs.#The galaxy is ours, Human. We were conquering and enslaving back before your kind had gotten out of the trees.#Be wary, Earther. The galaxy belongs to us. Interfere with our plans and we'll make you rue the day that you decided to walk upright.#</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Altarian">2</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Some have rumored that we're not nice. But really we are. Really nice. If we could meet, we'd even hug you!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME]. This galaxy belongs to us. Do not interfere or we shall take your pink skins and use them for our clothing.#The [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] have claimed all the galaxy. Get in our way and we'll crush you. We know of your home world and your similarity to the vile Humans.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] own this galaxy. The galaxy may not know this yet, but it is a fact. Your kind, with your soft pink skins, have no business being in space. You look a lot like the vile Humans who have interfered in our affairs too many times. Beware.#Your soft pink skin looks delicious. If I didn't know better, I'd think you were a Human. Hopefully your kind, while similar, has better sense.#We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and you are what? Nothing. Stay out of our way.#The galaxy belongs to us. Be wary of angering the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Torian">4</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We meet again. Our ancestors were very cruel to your ancestors. We hope we can become friends in time.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. Our past differences are should be put aside. Here, in space, we can now forge a new destiny.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Ah, so we meet again. Your kind made excellent slavelings. Get in our way and you'll find out just how easy we were on you.#Your pathetic kind has no business out in the stars. You should have been content with having your own planet. Do not get in our way.#Seeing your kind in the stars makes us laugh. Whenever I see your kind, I can't help but remember you as the slaves you were. Good times, good times...</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings. We have laid claim to much of the galaxy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. We have laid claim to much of the galaxy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Welcome to our galaxy. We have claimed all of it. Get in our way and we shall destroy you.#The galaxy is large, but so are our plans. Stay out of our way.#We are a powerful and evil race. That's right, I said evil. Let's say it together E-V-I-L. Doesn't that feel good? I mean evil.#We like bathe in the blood of our victims. We shall soon see if you are fodder for our annual bathes.#</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Welcome, Human friend! We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME]. We are always glad see you so that we can unravel the mystery of why we look so similar. We look forward to a great friendly relationship.#Our two peoples look very similar. There have been many stories told as to why. Given time, hopefully we will learn the truth.#Greetings, Human. The galaxy is a large place and together we can help guide its destiny.#Greetings! It appears we are ready to expand out into the galaxy together.#Greetings, I hope we can build a mutually beneficial relationship.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So, you're a Human. We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME]. We obviously have much in common based on our looks. We shall speak more soon.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME]. Clearly there is some relation between your race and ours. You're obviously some sort of backward failed subset of our species. Make one false step and we will cleanse you out of existence.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME]. Long have we considered expanding into the galaxy. Thanks to the humans, we now have that opportunity.#We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME]. Though, we do not ourselves call our world that for in our language it is the singular element. May peace go along your path.#Greetings. We have very little tolerance for the vile civilizations of the galaxy. Stay the path of righteous and all will be well. </Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. We have laid claim to much of the galaxy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Welcome to our galaxy. We have claimed all of it. Get in our way and we shall destroy you.#The galaxy is large, but so are our plans. Stay out of our way.#We are a powerful and evil race. That's right, I said evil. Let's say it together E-V-I-L. Doesn't that feel good? I mean evil.#We like bathe in the blood of our victims. We shall soon see if you are fodder for our annual bathes.#</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME], a proud and noble race. The Hyperdrive technology you Humans have created has created a great boom, but may indeed prove perilous to us all.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, so you are a Human. The species that created the Hyperdrive technology we now use to explore our galaxy. Do not get in our way though or you will earn our wrath.#We are a proud warrior civilization. We have nothing against you so long as you respect our power and wisdom.#Welcome, Human, to OUR galaxy.#The stars that you see are all claimed by us. Be wary before trespassing on any of the planets that orbit them.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Hmmm. So these weak, pink things are Humans. This galaxy has long been explored by the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and we will crush any who oppose us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Hello, Hunams!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hello, Hunams!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Hello, Hunams!. We have learned much from our Ur-Quan masters. In fact... Hmmm... Your skin looks... delicious!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Ah, the day has finally arrived for our paths to cross once more. While the scars of slavery are slow to heal, we believe that the crimes of the fathers should not be paid by the sons. Let this be the beginning of a prosperous new friendship between our two great nations.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So the rumors are true, the [YourEmpireName] has set out to find new planets to claim as their own. While some of our citizens are slow to forgive past atrocities, I would prefer to put aside our Drengin enslavement and look to a brighter future of hope and friendship. May our two nations continue to prosper.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Well, well, well... if it isn't our old 'friends', the Ur-Quan. Thousands of years of slavery at your hands will not be forgotten anytime soon. We suggest you keep your distance... or next time we meet our mercy may falter.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings. We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME]. We have been programmed for peace, love, and pleasure. We hope to have a lot of contact with your species.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, flesh creature. The [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] have made claims to many of these worlds. If we calculate that you are a threat to us, we will exterminate you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Fleshling, the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] have claimed these worlds. Interfere with our plans and we will liquefy your species to spread on our toast.#Carbon-form, this galaxy is ours. We have no love for organic life. Stay out of our way.#The future belongs to the cybernetic civilizations of the galaxy -- namely us.#Welcome Earth creature, gaze upon us for we are the future. That's enough looking. Now, stay out of our way.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Korx">6</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The galaxy is really, really big and business opportunities are everywhere. We hope to work with you to establish a profitable relationship.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The galaxy is positively very great big place and business opportunities are everywhere. We hope to work with you to establish a profitable relationship.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drath">7</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>You look very much like the Altarians who stole our world. If you cross us, we will make sure your death is swift.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You look very much like the Altarians who stole our world. If you cross us, we will make sure your death is swift.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You look very much like the Altarians who stole our world. If you cross us, we will make sure your death is swift.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Thalan">8</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We have come to this place and time to monitor you humans. The time of destruction nears.#You humans have no idea what you've done.  You are the source of the coming apocalypse.  Be wary, Earther, we are watching you.#You... are a Human? You recklessly provided these sub-races Hyperdrive technology? The chaos is at your feet. These creatures have no business out there. We have come... from somewhere else to help maintain a galactic balance.#You Humans are reckless. You have no idea what you have unleashed by providing hyperdrive to the galaxy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We have come to this place and time to monitor you humans. The time of destruction nears.#You humans have no idea what you've done.  You are the source of the coming apocalypse.  Be wary, Earther, we are watching you.#You... are a Human? You recklessly provided these sub-races Hyperdrive technology? The chaos is at your feet. These creatures have no business out there. We have come... from somewhere else to help maintain a galactic balance.#You Humans are reckless. You have no idea what you have unleashed by providing hyperdrive to the galaxy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We have come to this place and time to monitor you humans. The time of destruction nears.#You humans have no idea what you've done.  You are the source of the coming apocalypse.  Be wary, Earther, we are watching you.#You... are a Human? You recklessly provided these sub-races Hyperdrive technology? The chaos is at your feet. These creatures have no business out there. We have come... from somewhere else to help maintain a galactic balance.#You Humans are reckless. You have no idea what you have unleashed by providing hyperdrive to the galaxy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Iconian">9</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Hail, Human traveler. We are thankful that your wonderful invention, Hyperdrive, has finally reached us. Now we can once more go into the stars and hopefully reclaim our worlds from the vile Yor.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hail, Human traveler. We are thankful that your wonderful invention, Hyperdrive, has finally reached us. Now we can once more go into the stars and hopefully reclaim our worlds from the vile Yor.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Hail, Human traveler. We are thankful that your wonderful invention, Hyperdrive, has finally reached us. Now we can once more go into the stars and hopefully reclaim our worlds from the vile Yor.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings, Human friend - we meet at long last! We are the humble [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and we have laid claim to several worlds throughout the galaxy. May this be the start of a great friendship between our two civilizations.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So, Human, we meet at long last. We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and we have claimed these worlds in our name. Let both our civilizations flourish and prosper in the centuries to come.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>So, Human, we meet at long last. We are the mighty [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and we have claimed these worlds in our name. Beware!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We send you a very warm welcome, Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER]. I am sure we'll get along splendidly.#Hello, Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER] As our old saying goes "May a cuddle be your guide".#Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER]. We welcome you.#Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER] - we meet at long last! We are the humble [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and we have laid claim to several worlds throughout the galaxy. May this be the start of a great friendship between our two civilizations.#We are glad to see you amongst the stars. We hope to work with you in the future.#Greetings! We are pleased to meet you.#Welcome! We look forward to a long relationship.#The galaxy is plenty big enough for us all to live together in.#Peace and love for you and all your kind.#We are very pleased to meet you. Our gentle civilization wants only peace.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER], we meet at long last. We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and we have claimed these worlds in our name. Let both our civilizations flourish and prosper in the centuries to come.#We hope we can live together in harmony. If not, we'll crush you like a bug.#We look forward to working with you.#Greetings. This galaxy is a big place but I'm not sure it's big enough for both of us.#I am sure we will get along great, Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER]. On the other hand, if we don't get along, there's always a long drawn out genocidal war. We're good either way.#Howdy Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER]. We're still learning your language. Howdy. I like that. Anyway, we hope to establish a mutually agreeable relationship.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>So [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER], we meet at long last. We are the mighty [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and we have claimed these worlds in our name. Beware!#We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME]. This galaxy and all that live in it are ours. Interfere and you will die.# The [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] exists to enslave all inferiors. We will soon learn if you are amongst them.#We are the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] . We are what you would call EVIL. Frankly, we think we've gotten a bad rap. Sure, we like to kill and eat other sentient beings for our amusement. Sure, we enslave the weak. And yes, we consider tormenting to be a hobby. But does that really make us evil?#So you are Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER]. I have heard about you. Well, as you may know, we are in short supply of bone powder. We like the grind up the flesh of our enemies. So how you doing?#So you are Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER]. We have claimed this planet..er..star..er galaxy. Yes. This entire galaxy. In fact, you're standing right inside the galaxy right this very minute. That's ours.#We pretty much like to exterminate everyone. It causes us some uncomfortable times when on diplomatic missions. You know, "Hello, how you doing? Oh, sorry about your mate...and your off spring...and your pets." and from there it's just an awkward silence as you try to find the Xandar ambassador which, of course you can't because the humans wiped them out. I'm just saying, it's not easy being blood thirsty. We have our own set of issues to deal with.#Whohaha. Greetings, [LISTENING_RACE_LEADER]. I was reading up on your civilization. I hear that at one time you thought that violence was a reflection of a primitive society. Well, I hate to be the one to break this to you but the only reason I haven't killed you is because we're dozens of light years apart. What can I say, the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] just likes to kill things.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Korath">13</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>This is [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] territory.  You have been warned.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This is [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] territory.  I will not point this out again.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>This is [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] territory.  You will be held responsible for trespassing.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Krynn">14</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Hello, [YourLeaderName].  I'm sure there is enough room in this quadrant for both the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME] and the [YourEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Keep your greed in check [YourLeaderName], and you'll find there is room for both of our races to prosper.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>This area was claimed long ago by the [SPEAKING_RACE_NAME], you should remove your ships immediately.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="B_DEMAND_EQUAL">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>The [YourEmpireName] can make your life a lot easier if you donate the following supplies, or a lot worse if you refuse:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We must ask that you provide our civilization with certain supplies... refusal will be frowned upon:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We request that you hand over following supplies... or else:</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="B_DEMAND_STRONGER">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>It would be in your people's best interest to donate several supplies to our nation:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>On our world, it is customary for the weaker to give presents to the stronger. The gifts we would like from you include:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Well, slave race, we think you should provide your superior with some nice things. These, for instance:</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="B_DEMAND_WEAKER">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We may be weak, but if we really need these supplies, and will have to take action against you if you don't give them over:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Even though you could crush us like a bug, we are going to ask that you hand over the following:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>If you don't give us the following supplies, I'll punch you so hard your grandmother will feel it! Don't you dare laugh at me, cause I'll do it! This is what you will give me:</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_LOWDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>That's right... I, the Glorious and Wise [YourLeaderName] have descended from on high to grace you with this terrific bargain. If you're smarter than you look, you'll take it:#I, [YourLeaderName] the Wise have decided to make a deal it'll be hard for your kind to refuse:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hey buddy, we're interested in trading stuff with you. Here's what we are thinking:#OK, I'm gonna put this on the table, and you tell me if you'd wanna trade or not:#Have I got a sweet deal for you, friend! Here's what I wanna trade:#When you see this deal, you're probably going to wet yourself, [TheirLeaderName]:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>This is what I want from you, and this is what I'm going to give you for it:#Your empire has some stuff that I want, and I'm feeling generous so perhaps I'll even give you something in return. My deal is as follows:#I'm used to bargaining with a laser-pistol and a boot to the face, but for the [TheirEmpireName] I'll try to negotiate properly:</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_MIDDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. We are interested in trading with you. Here's what we're thinking:#We are interested in trading with you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_HIGHDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, Excellency. On behalf of the [YourEmpireName] we would like to trade these items:</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_GIVE_GIFT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We're a peaceful nation, [TheirLeaderName], and want to present you with these gifts to express the deep bond we feel with the [TheirEmpireName]:#We humbly present the following gifts to the noble [TheirLeaderName]:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hello, friend. Our civilization would like to give you the following gifts:#Greetings, [TheirLeaderName]. On behalf of the [YourEmpireName] I present you with the following:#Greetings, friend! Our humble nation presents you with the following gifts:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Here's some free stuff... my advisors said people like you appreciate gestures of 'kindness'. These things now belong to you:#I don't quite get it, but I read that other races like giving and receiving presents. I thought I'd try it out and give you:#Take it, I insist:#I'm not too good at this... but, I wanted you, to... have this gift... as a token... of... friendship. Wow, that wasn't so difficult!#We'd like to give you some goodies, it's a tradition amongst our people.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_STRONGER_LOWDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We are a good civilization, and in being good we've decided to grant you forgiveness for the sins of your army. Our wisdom is great, and yours isn't (otherwise you'd probably be winning this war) so we suggest you accept our request and put an end to the war. If you don't, it'll make us sad, and a bit steamed, and we'll probably take it out on you. Just being honest.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Good god, we're just so totally kicking your butts. Now, look at the left and right sides of your terminal and we can discuss a peace treaty. Did I mention you guys just completely suck when it comes to war? I mean really, what the hell were you thinking fighting us? Hello!?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Cower before the mighty [YourLeaderName], you stinky, stupid [TheirShortCivName] scum. That's right, the wise and smart leader of the super strong [YourEmpireName] is here to offer you a way out of this war... which I should remind you, you're LOSING! You should take it, if you even have any brain cells in that stupid head of yours.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_EQUAL_LOWDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Our infinite wisdom about peace and nature and stuff has shown us the truth about something... this war SUCKS. And the suckiness is equal for both sides, it seems, so let's come to terms and put an end to this pointless feud once and for all.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Golly gee, the war really ain't goin' too well for either of us. Lots of explosions and stuff. Reminds me of the time I tried cooking a firecracker in the nano-wave oven. Hooooo-wee. Anywhoo, let's come to terms.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Er... hey there [TheirLeaderName]... now, don't turn off the U.T., I only came to talk. We're both pretty good fighters, and... it just seems... this war isn't really going well for either of us. I'm not proud of it, but my elite fighting army of super evil warriors apparently just isn't up to snuff. I don't even remember why we started in the first place! So, what do you say we put down our weapons, call a truce, and aim our sights on the weaker fish in the galaxy?#Well this war is becoming quite problematic, [TheirLeaderName]. Let is come to terms.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_WEAKER_LOWDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>OK [TheirLeaderName], we deserved the attacks, the invasions, and all the destruction this war has caused. But, now we see the error in our ways... we completely understand why we needed to be attacked, and now we can overcome and prosper. Nothing feels better than to forgive and forget! So what do you say - shake on it?#Let's talk for a minute, OK [TheirLeaderName]? Now, you obviously like to prove your strength through aggressive means. By picking on races weaker than you (us for example) you can ignore the fact that your real enemy... is yourself. Don't bottle up your sadness and depression only to release it as anger on someone else. Let's put an end to this silly war so you can start down a new path towards happiness.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Please stop hurting us! If you keep doing the stuff you're doing you'll conquer all our territory. Er, yea, I see that probably would be a good thing for you. But, think of the children! Won't SOMEONE please think of the children?!#Make the pain stop.#Would you please quit destroying our civilization?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Well this is just great... I have to put all my super evil plans on hold while you guys just steamroll through my empire like a bunch of... well... steamrollers. Let's just stop all this hating, and let me get back to doing what I do best... picking on aliens weaker than me. Which certainly doesn't include you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_STRONGER_MIDDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>My strategists have informed me that our war against your empire is going great... for us, at least. For you, well, it just seems to be hopeless. But, with great power comes the responsibility to be just and merciful. Since we're SO frightfully powerful, we should probably be EXTRA merciful. Let's figure how your people can escape this grim war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The war doesn't seem to be going so well for you. But, we are prepared to sign an armistice today. Cause we're just that nice.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>I've got you right where I want you, [TheirLeaderName]. My forces are breathing down your neck, and you're just sweating like a cornered rat. But, here's the real surprise: I'm going to let you go. I've had my fun, and provided you agree to my terms, you're free to live a peaceful, albeit pathetic, existence.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_EQUAL_MIDDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Both of our nations are suffering due to this war. Let's stop it before things get really ugly.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Let us come to terms and end this awful war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You're pretty good at this war thing... practically my equal. Let's not draw things out. We should come to terms and conserve our strength for other battles.#We are in a stalemate, let us end this conflict now so we can move to better things.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_WEAKER_MIDDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Our people are tired of this destructive war. What are your terms for peace, oh Merciful [TheirLeaderName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have amply demonstrated your power. Perhaps there is a way we can end this destructive conflict?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You should be proud of your vile army - they have us beat. My army is weak, my people are tired. What will it take to end this war?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_STRONGER_HIGHDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings, [TheirLeaderName], leader of the [TheirEmpireName]. As you know, our forces have been able to out-maneuver your forces at every turn. The blood of your troops spills like a river because you are too proud to admit defeat. We are here to offer you redemption. Let us come to peaceful terms so your people's suffering can end.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. This misunderstanding between us has caused great harm. We could crush your civilization but we are not without mercy. The time has come for us to set aside our differences and forge a better future.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Let it be known that the powerful [YourLeaderName] is not without mercy. While our forces await my order to attack, I'm here to give you a way to escape my fury. Let us come to peaceful terms so your citizens can live another day.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_EQUAL_HIGHDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings, [TheirLeaderName]. Our forces seem to be in stale-mate, neither side making headway against the other. Let us come to terms and save our people the suffering of a drawn-out war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. This misunderstanding between us has caused great harm. The time has come for us to set aside our differences and forge a better future.#Let us find a way to end this terrible war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You have proven yourself, [TheirLeaderName]. We seem to be dancing around each other, each bloody battle getting our forces nowhere. Let's withdrawal our forces and save our strength other wars.#You are powerful, [TheirLeaderName]. But the time has come to put our differences aside.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_TRADE_PEACE_WEAKER_HIGHDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings, merciful leader of the [TheirEmpireName]. You have proven your might beyond question, so for the good of our people we humbly request an end to the war, no matter the cost.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, your Excellency. Your prowess on the battlefield knows no bounds. Let us celebrate your strength by agreeing to terms and constructing a new galactic order based on your strength, wisdom and most importantly, mercy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>As a warrior myself, I know when I've been outmaneuvered. You're a cunning adversary, [TheirLeaderName]. Let us come to terms so your forces may unleash their might on a more worthy opponent than I.#You are indeed very powerful and you have defeated us. We are prepared to come to terms favorable to you.#You have impressed us with your great power. Let us find a way to negotiate an end to this war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SNEER_RELATIONS_VERYLOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Gah! I never get used to seeing your disgusting green mug up on my vid screen, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Altarian">2</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Just because we share facial features doesn't mean I have to trust you.#Ah, our space cousins... like uninvited guests to a family party. What is it?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Torian">4</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This better not be more whining about how you 'used to be slaves for the Ur-Quan Hierarchy but broke free'. Just cut to the chase, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Iconian">9</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Gah! I never get used to seeing your disgusting green mug up on my vid screen, [YourLeaderName], but don't take this as an insult.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Jeeze, not the [YourEmpireName] again.#Make it quick [YourLeaderName] before I get tempted to press the big red button.#Gross... not another alien.#I'm glad there's about 10 billion light years between us cause you're one of the UGLIEST things I've EVER seen.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Gak. What in the farg do you pathetic Humans want?#You're not dead yet? Oh hold on, sorry, getting ahead of myself.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Farg'n sluzz. What do you want now, [YourLeaderName]... I really don't have time for more [YourShortCivName] bull-gark!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What do our backwards, smelly, soft, distant, inbred Human cousins wish to speak of today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, a lesser life-form. What do you want, [YourLeaderName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What does the talking monkey wish to speak to us about?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, [YourLeaderName]... out to spread your foul stench amongst decent life-forms?#Your kind disgusts me, [YourLeaderName]... say what you must, and make it quick.#How can you expect us to negotiate with such an despicable being as yourself, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Altarian">2</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What does the magical talking monkey wish to speak to us about?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>My patience runs thin... state your intentions, [YourLeaderName].#What do you want to talk about now?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Just because you gave us hyperdrive doesn't mean I have to enjoy talking to you.#Your gift of hyperdrive means little to us. We owe your kind nothing.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You?! Make your case swiftly, [YourLeaderName]... we don't bargain with YOUR kind.#Oh, back to enslave us again, you stupid green barbarian?!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What now? Didn't you see the sign on the comm panel?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Fleshling creature. We have granted you this time speak to us. Use it wisely.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>State your intentions, green one.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>[YourLeaderName], We have granted you this time speak to us. Use it wisely.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Oh it's you. Our occupation forces were just getting set up.#We really look forward to making use of your planets.#Dead man walking. Speak.#We promise that we will treat your people humanely after we liberate them from you. But in the meantime, what do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Make it quick, [YourLeaderName].#Aren't you dead? Oh, no. Sorry, that's tomorrow. Nevermind that.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>What a coincidence, we were just assigning commanders for occupation duties on your worlds. What do you want?#I thought you died. Oh well, there's always tomorrow.#We were just reading up on how you bury your dead. Not that it really matters since we'll be incinerating you soon enough.#Now would be a good time for you to do some serious sucking up. Just a tip.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SNEER_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hello [YourLeaderName] the alien . What can you do for us today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Good slarf, what do you want? There's a game on that I really wanted to watch...</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, cousin. As a charity-loving civilization, we are always interested in talking to our inferiors.#Ah yes, good to see you figured out how to turn those knobs, cousin.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What do our future vassals want? Anything for you guys, I mean really...#You know, a good servant is not seen or heard. Just thought I'd mention that. No charge.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Yesssssss?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Yes? If you have trouble speaking, try sounding out the words from your primitive terminal.#Speak.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You organic creatures are inefficient at communication but we have granted you the honor of communication. Speak quickly.#I still can't believe it. Talking meat.#So you communicate by moving a piece of meat in your mouth? That creates sounds? Interesting.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SNEER_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, it's you. What do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What does the talking monkey want today? Well, speak up!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What pearls of wisdom can we impart to little old you today?#Always delighted to educate the less fortunate.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You primitive Humans always amuse us with your mouth flapping. What would you like to discuss today?#Yeees?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>The galaxy is a perilous place. We are happy to speak to you but be aware that your relative weakness makes you vulnerable to others. You should strengthen your defenses.#How can we help our relatively weak friends?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I'm listening, [YourLeaderName].#Just so you are aware, we could crush you like a bug. Not saying we will, just that we could.#Do you have any idea how lucky you are that we like you -- currently? We are vastly more powerful than you.#Always willing to take a second out of our busy schedule of managing the galaxy to talk to its weakest members.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>What, [YourLeaderName]?#Just so you are aware, we could crush you like a bug. Not saying we will, just that we could.#Do you have any idea how lucky you are that we like you -- currently? We are vastly more powerful than you.#Always willing to take a second out of our busy schedule of managing the galaxy to talk to its weakest members.#We're sizing you up right now for invasion. Just so you know. Why am I telling you this? Because you are so weak that if we wanted to squash you, it would be easy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SNEER_RELATIONS_GOOD">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The week wouldn't be complete without some alien transmission, and it looks like you're the one!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are always glad to see our friends, the Humans, up on their hind legs.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. How can we help you today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Welcome. We are always pleased to give guidance to our friends.#How's that rash working out for you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Ah, our friends from the [YourEmpireName]. We hope you received our gift, a big red bouncing ball. Did you bounce the ball? We felt that such entertainments would amuse your kind.#Can you sing for me?#Do a little dance for us. It amuses us.#Ah, your antics are always amusing. What do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are always amused to discuss things with our organic friends.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, [YourLeaderName]. Always glad to talk with some of the average civilizations of the galaxy... see what's on their minds.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SNEER_RELATIONS_ALLY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings! Is there something the [YourEmpireName] needs our help with?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Welcome, 'ally'. What do you need from us this time?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What aid can we provide to you today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>How may we aid our cheese-eating, surrender-monkey allies today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You again. Well, since we're allegedly allies I suppose I should talk to you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What does the parasite want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Until you can muster a stronger military I guess we can help you out. What is it you require?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GROVEL_RELATIONS_VERYLOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>[YourLeaderName]! I'm frankly quite surprised to be hearing from you. What do you need from the meager [TheirEmpireName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What does the powerful, yet benevolent, [YourLeaderName] wish to speak to us mere Drengin about?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Warm greetings from your close, friendly, and caring galactic brothers. How can we work together to create a better future for one another?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are unworthy to even speak to you. Please let us know how we can be of service to the peaceful [YourEmpireName] who we hope don't want to enslave us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What do our god-like friends, the [YourEmpireName], overlords of the universe who are aware that we were once brutally enslaved and would never want to see us pitiful beings enslaved again, wish from us today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What does the surprisingly powerful yet peace loving [YourLeaderName] wish to convey to us machines?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We aim only to please the powerful [YourEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GROVEL_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What would the Humans, overlords of the galaxy, like to chat about today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, [YourLeaderName]. We are willing to talk about anything you would like to talk about. The virtual floor is yours.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>How can we be of service to the mighty [YourLeaderName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I don't feel I'm even worthy to speak to such great and powerful beings. But I will try my best. How may we humbly serve you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What can we modest artificial beings do for the powerful [YourEmpireName] today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, mighty [YourLeaderName]. For what business do you require our humble empire?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GROVEL_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Wow, it's [YourLeaderName]! Can I get your autograph?! Er... I guess not... sorry, I'm kinda new to this 'alien communication' thing. Is there anything the [TheirEmpireName] can do for you, today, sir, anything at all?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. Your humble and obviously related friends are always interested in discussing anything you might wish.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>How may we serve your whims today, oh great and powerful [YourLeaderName]?#We're at your disposal. I mean that figuratively of course.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, powerful one. How can we help one another today?#Whatever you want to do today is good for us. I mean, as long as you're not going to do anything TO us that is. Heh. I always get this way when I'm nervous.#What's up, oh great and powerful one?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, O Great [YourLeaderName]. What can we humbly do for you today?#We are always here to serve at your whims, [YourLeaderName].#What may we humbly do for you today, [YourLeaderName]?#You are looking even better than usual. I mean, you look great. Not that I'm saying that you ever look bad. Look, just don't hurt me.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GROVEL_RELATIONS_GOOD">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hi! Glad to see you! Here's a big virtual hug!#You complete me.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hello, my friend. How may your galactic brothers be at your service today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, Human friends. We are always glad to talk to you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are always happy to see our friends from the [YourEmpireName] willing to speak to us lowly [TheirShortCivName]s.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, [YourLeaderName]. How can we assist you today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>When it comes to talking to the leader of the mighty [YourEmpireName], the pleasure is all ours.#Greetings, friend of the [TheirEmpireName]. A being of your majesty is always, always welcome here.#Oooh, we always love to talk to the wonderful, magical [YourEmpireName].#Good to see you. Have we told you today that you guys rock? No really, you guys are awesome.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GROVEL_RELATIONS_ALLY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hail [YourLeaderName], the powerful leader of the [YourEmpireName]! What assistance do you need from your faithful allies, the Humans?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Oh great ally, how can we help you in your cause to unite the galaxy?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>It is always great to see our galactic brothers. How might we work together to unite the galaxy today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We bid welcome to our Human ally. What can we do to aid our united effort to bring the galaxy peace and justice?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We welcome our most honorable, wonderful ally who we worship as a god. How might we serve our valiant cause? We are yours to command.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, carbon-based ally.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings to our powerful ally from the [YourEmpireName]. How can we help you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GREETING_RELATIONS_VERYLOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So... the green thing wants to talk.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Altarian">2</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our common appearance doesn't reflect the startling differences between the Human race and your inept society. State your case quickly.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What is it? And I mean literally... what ARE you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Yor">5</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Request for discussion acknowledged.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Request for discussion acknowledged.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Yor">5</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You robots disgust me. What do you want?#I can't believe I'm talking to a robot.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>My time and energy is precious... I hope you haven't come to waste either of them.#Aren't you almost dead yet? Well, at the very least, we wish you were dead.#We thought you died.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What do you want?#What is it now, [YourLeaderName]?#I have much more important things to do, [YourLeaderName]. Make it quick.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Speak quick... my tolerance for your kind wavers.#I don't have time for your lip-flapping.#We hate you.#Well, we were just plotting your demise, what do you want now?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GREETING_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I'm just glad the Comm Terminal only transfers video and sound. The moment this thing starts sending smells I'm just going to quit.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hey, you crazy lookin' alien! What's up?#Good god man. I mean, what the hell are you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You pink-skinned creatures are just utterly disgusting. But your skin sure looks good.#What do you Earth creatures want now???#Aren't you dead yet?#You know, I saw a picture of your mate and for a second I thought they were a Drengin.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are the mighty Drengin. Don't waste our time.#It's good to see you made it here on your hind legs.#We're very busy plotting your demise, what do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We currently don't know what to make of you Humans. You look like us but you do not have our intelligence or strength or abilities. Despite your obvious failings, we still are willing to speak to you -- for now.#Our inferior cousins wish to speak to us? What?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What can we do for you?#What do you want?#State your business.#Yes?#I hope no one sees me talking to you.#Yikes, I always forget how weird looking you are.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Because you gave us Hyperdrive technology, we are willing to speak to you.#You Humans have been a great disappointment to us.#We are amazed at how ugly some of your cities are, I mean really, what's the deal with Las Vegas?#What do you Humans want?#Yes?#What?#Speak up.#Now what do you want?#I'm getting tired of conversing with you, state your business.#Our peoples are not friendly. For your sake, I hope you are hear to rectify that.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What?#Yes?#We Arceans are a proud and noble race, do not push your luck.#Speak up!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You do know that the only way that the crimes of your kind against us will be solved is through the shedding of much Drengin blood.#Soon we shall have our revenge against what you did to our world, Drengin scum.#What do you want slaver?#Did you hear our newest song, "A Dead Drengin Makes a Happy Day"? It has a nice beat.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We have thrown off the Drengin and now we make our way to the stars. Based on the trajectory of our relations, your kind may soon be at war with us.#What do you want?#Greetings.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You flesh creatures make no sense to us. The ultimate form of life is mechanical. We live forever while your flesh begins to rot from the moment you hatch or whatever it is you do.#Your existence is annoying to us so don't bother us unless you have something important to say.#You Humans are very inefficient so be brief.#Ah, talking meat. Crazy stuff.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Terminal open for communications.#State your business flesh creature.#Our efficiency is nearly maxed out, be careful not to waste our time.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We're not particularly fond of you, so please be quick.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What do you fleshlings wish to discuss today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>My tolerance for your kind is very low. Don't waste my time.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Yes?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You Drengin, it's hard believe you are even bipedal.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>I have many things to do, [YourLeaderName]... please make it quick.#We're both busy leaders, [YourLeaderName], so I'm sure you'll understand when I ask you to hurry up with whatever it is you came for.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Yes, [YourLeaderName]?#Well, if it isn't [YourLeaderName]. What do you need?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Make it quick... I have little time to spare for the [YourEmpireName].#I'm listening... you can start flapping your lips whenever.#I have rusty daggers sharper than you, [YourLeaderName]... get to talking before I lose patience.#This better be REALLY important.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GREETING_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, the Ur-Quan or Kzer-Za, or however you name your civilization. We consider ourselves pretty diplomatic but we've seen how you are. So you'll have to excuse me if I have a lack of enthusiasm for talking to you.#Ah [YourLeaderName], glad you were able to find some time away from oppressing people to speak to us.#You do know that now that the [TheirEmpireName] is out in the galaxy that your reign of terror in the universe will be coming to an end right?#The other day I saw someone driving a really old truck. Don't see many wheeled vehicles on Earth anymore. Anyway, the driver swerved out of his way to run over a turtle. I thought to myself, I bet that's [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Yor">5</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, the [YourEmpireName]. We've seen your efficient way of exterminating the galaxy. Not very nice.#So, the [YourEmpireName] are taking time out from their genocidal schedule to speak to us?#When I pulled up the schedule and saw your face it took me a second to realize it was the [YourEmpireName]. I had hoped it was the Meklar or something.#Greetings, robot boy. What can we do for the [YourEmpireName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hey, [YourLeaderName]! What do you feel like discussing... politics, religion, your favorite vid-shows? I'm good for about 20 minutes till my next meeting.#How you doing? What do you want to talk about?#I may look like I have no arms, but the [TheirEmpireName] has a long reach.#Good to see you again. How might I help you?#We humans are always interested in forging ties.#Greetings  [YourLeaderName]. What can we do for you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We would love to snuggle with you. Our kind is always known for being snuggly.#Hello, what may we do for you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Well Human, what business can we discuss on this day?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Ah, the Earth fleshling. What do you want?#For you and your delicious looking skin, anything.#Ah, Earther, what would you like?#Holy cow are you humans ugly. What do you want?#Ack. Human. I apologize. Still not used to looking at your kind.#I hear that your kind doesn't eat the skin of its criminals as punishment. Pity.#Did you get my free subscription to Atrocity Weekly?#Some people don't understand us. We torture because we love.#I'm having a case of the Monday's. I've explained to my underlings that the beatings will continue until their joy returns.#Greetings [YourLeaderName]. We just got a new Death Furnace installed. That ought to improve morale here. It certainly has improved mine. Who do you need killed today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Torian">4</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>It's weird even talking to someone that we consider prey.#So the [YourEmpireName] are still hoping to build some sort of place in our galaxy? You were slaves before and you'll be slaves again. But, in the meantime, what do you want?#You Torians are delicious. I've had many for dinner. You go great with Chianti.#What?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>How are our guests doing? By guest, I mean this galaxy is already owned by us and so we are allowing you to occupy some unused part of it.#Did you receive your copy of Pillage Weekly? It's my favorite magazine.#I don't have a lot to say today so let me just be blunt, what do you want?#You know whose skin tastes good? Torian skin. Wow, are they tasty!#Keep an eye out for Humans. They're slippery.#What can the all powerful [TheirEmpireName] do for you today?#The [TheirEmpireName] are powerful and I, [TheirLeaderName] am very busy. What do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings, Earther. We are always glad to speak with our human cousins.#Good afternoon, [YourLeaderName]. What can we do for you today?#Greetings, [YourLeaderName].  We are always glad to talk to the [YourEmpireName].#What can we do for the [YourEmpireName] today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Be brief, villain.#Shouldn't you be kicking a puppy right now?#You guys are such a caricature of generic evil that if I wasn't seeing you with my own eyes I'd think you were just the result of some lame Sci-Fi hack's imagination. Cough.#Don't you have some slaves to beat?#Glad to see you were able to take some time out from your busy schedule of pillaging.#Ever thought of just wearing a skull mask? It would complete the effect of being a total villain.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drath">7</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>You don't still want your planet back do you? It's ours now.#We really don't have much patience for talking to your reptilian kind.#What can the [TheirEmpireName] do for you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Hello there. We don't know much about you yet, but we are eager to negotiate with you.#The galaxy is a large place and you are a newcomer on the scene, how can we serve you?#Good to see you again, how might we help?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hello! Always pleased to talk to you. What would you like to discuss today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The [YourEmpireName] has our attention. What can we do for you?#What does the [YourEmpireName] want from the mighty [TheirEmpireName]?#Our ancient and glorious civilization has been out here far longer than yours -- as you know. But your Hyperdrive technology we appreciate. What would you like to discuss?#What would you like to discuss today, Earther?#What can the [TheirEmpireName] do for you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Don't you have someone to enslave?#I really don't like talking to you. Just thought I'd let you know that.#Yes?#What?#What do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I greet you, [YourLeaderName]. What items would you care to communicate to us today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We really don't care for those who once enslaved us. What do you want?#The slavers wish to talk? What then?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Yor">5</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>What do the talking robots want?#Yes?#What can we do for [YourLeaderName] today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Transmission open. State your intentions.#What?#Don't let the other races fool you, we aren't a bunch of whimpering people looking for sympathy. I mean, just because the Drengin conquered and enslaved us for 30,000 years and destroyed most of our planet, why should people feel sorry for us? I mean, sure, only horrible people wouldn't want to help us but you're not horrible... are you?#What can we do for you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>How may we operate for you today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Yes?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Talking meat. I still can't get over it. I mean, you actually use meat to talk in your meat mouth. It's just weird. You were saying?#What is it you want, human?#What does the biological unit wish to discuss?#Ack. Humans. What?#Shouldn't you be excreting somewhere? What do the [YourEmpireName] want?#Topics of conversation listed on your terminal.#Input data.#Speak.#Yes?#Awaiting input.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Iconian">9</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>I thought we had already wiped your kind out. We are patient though.#It appears there was a flaw in our programming as I thought that we had long ago eliminated the [YourEmpireName].#What do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>How might we pleasure you today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. Topics of conversation are listed on your terminal.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Topics of conversation listed on your terminal.#Input data.#Speak.#Yes?#Awaiting input.#Talking meat. An amazing accident of the universe.#Ah, you a Drengin or Human or what? All of you meat-based creatures look the same to us.#Why are all you people humanoid fleshlings? Why not a silicon-based civilization? Or a gas-based civilization? But no, there's us, the [TheirEmpireName] and then a bunch of talking meat creatures.#What do you need, fleshling? This galaxy is full of fleshlings. Not much variety. There was rumor of a civilization called the "Siliconoids" or something like that, crystalline-based life. But no, I get to talk to fleshlings. So what do you want?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Korx">6</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Ah, humans. You know, until you guys showed up we were the only game in town in terms of being merchants. You humans with your pathetic sense of "fair play" are messing things up.#You humans are making it tougher to gouge people into oblivion.#What do you guys want? To match wits with us in trade? Bring it on.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Korx">6</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Ah, you're new in this galaxy. Good. Good. Don't let those rumors that we sell unsafe products disturb you. People are just jealous of us. Could I interest you in a bag of glass for your offspring?#Greetings. There are those who say we're unscrupulous. But when our products kill 20% of a planet's population, they forget about the 80% that weren't harmed. Much.#What can we sell you today?#Hey [YourLeaderName]. Good to see you. Some people nicknamed me crazy [TheirLeaderName]. Why? Because all this stuff has got to go! Need slaves? I've got them!#Need someone "taken care of"? Let me know.#The rumors of the planets we've destroyed are false. Rumors planted by the survivors.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Thalan">8</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>You humans and your crusading nature are dangerous. We are not fooled by your diplomatic exterior.#You may not realize this but you humans have set into motion a series of events that will end in the destruction of the galaxy!#You humans have no business being out here. Ruin and destruction follows in your wake.#What do the reckless humans want?#You should never have given these child races hyperdrive. But then again, you should not be here either.#What do you want?#Yes?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You humans and your crusading nature are dangerous. We are not fooled by your diplomatic exterior.#You may not realize this but you humans have set into motion a series of events that will end in the destruction of the galaxy!#You humans have no business being out here. Ruin and destruction follows in your wake.#What do the reckless humans want?#You should never have given these child races hyperdrive. But then again, you should not be here either.#What do you want?#Yes?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You humans and your crusading nature are dangerous. We are not fooled by your diplomatic exterior.#You may not realize this but you humans have set into motion a series of events that will end in the destruction of the galaxy!#You humans have no business being out here. Ruin and destruction follows in your wake.#What do the reckless humans want?#You should never have given these child races hyperdrive. But then again, you should not be here either.#What do you want?#Yes?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Thalan">8</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Sigh, another child race in the galaxy. We have a lot of work to do. What do you want?#Beware of the Humans. How can we help?#Yes?#Greetings, [YourLeaderName].#Well [YourLeaderName], if your civilization has to be out there, I guess we can see how we can work together.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Iconian">9</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I don't know you, [YourLeaderName]. But this is an opportunity to change that.#The [YourEmpireName] are new to this galaxy. Though with a name like that, I suspect you'll have a lot of... ahem... impact.#Greetings. How can we assist the [YourEmpireName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Oh, it's you, [YourLeaderName]. To what do I owe the visit?#It's always a pleasure to talk with the [YourEmpireName].#We are always happy to talk to the [YourEmpireName]. What can we do for you?#What can we do for you on this glorious day?#Happy days. Glad to see you.#What's up, [YourLeaderName]?#Glad to see you again [YourLeaderName]. How can we be of service?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hello, [YourLeaderName]. What do you wish to discuss today?#What can the mighty [TheirEmpireName] do for you?#The [TheirEmpireName] is powerful and very busy but we are interested in hearing what you have to say.#What would you like to talk about?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>I thought I could smell you comin', [YourLeaderName].#What does your kind want?#What do the [YourEmpireName] need now?#My time is short and we don't really like talking to inferiors. State your business.#Get to the point.#You wouldn't believe what I read in Torture Today Magazine. But it's a long story. What's up?#Please be brief, I've had a bad day, one of our slaves acted up and we had to burn off his limbs to teach him a lesson.#Can you believe there are some civilizations that think eating other beings is wrong?#Wow. I mean, yikes you really are an ugly creature aren't you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GREETING_RELATIONS_GOOD">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Howdy, friend! I always have time to shoot the breeze with my pal, [YourLeaderName].#Good to see you. You should come down to Texas sometime and have some steaks.#Whoa. Sorry, just not quite used to seeing aliens looking at me.#Hey, [YourLeaderName]. How's it going?#Ever sing the lumberjack song? I guess not.#On Earth we have a saying, don't judge a book by its cover. Hoowee glad we're sticking to that.#I hope you're hear for trade. We like trade. And my gold plated rocket car doesn't pay for itself.#Hola!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Oh, we may not look cuddly, but we love you so much that if you were really here we'd want to snuggle!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, friend. How can we help each other today? I've got some of those 'art' holo-films you like so much!#How you doing?#I never thought I'd like anyone but you, [YourLeaderName], seem to be my kind of alien.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, fellow sentient. What should we discuss today?#So what's up?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Hello [YourLeaderName]. How can the [TheirEmpireName] help you today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, friend. How can we help each other today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Hey, buddy! Come to shoot the breeze, or just to compare trophies of war? I have a great collection of skulls mounted above my flame-pit.#You sly dog, always great to hear from the [YourEmpireName]. What'dya wanna talk about?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GREETING_RELATIONS_ALLY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, Ally. How might we work together today?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CRY_FOR_HELP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Arcean">3</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, [YourLeaderName]. While the Acrean and Drengin civilizations have had their past differences, we come to you with a proposition of brotherhood. The foul [OtherLeaderName] has relentlessly attacked us, spilling the blood of our people and threatening our very existence. We humbly request your aide in this losing war.#Hello, merciful leader of the [YourShortCivName] People. We come to you in the shadow of war, as the [OtherEmpireName] have threatened to destroy our great civilization. Shall we put our past differences aside and untie against these malicious beasts?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, [YourLeaderName]. While the Drengin and Acrean civilizations have had their past differences, we come to you with a proposition of brotherhood. The foul [OtherLeaderName] has relentlessly attacked us, bringing our civilization to the brink of ruin. We ask for your aide in this losing battle.# Hello, merciful leader of the Drengin People. We come to you in the shadow of war, as the [OtherEmpireName] has threatened our very existence. Shall we put our past differences aside and untie against this vicious warmonger?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hello, friend. We are slowly being destroyed by the [OtherEmpireName]. Is there anything you can do to help us?#The war against the [OtherEmpireName] is going badly. My advisors have informed me that they do not expect us to be able to hold out much longer against [OtherLeaderName]'s forces. Is there anything you can do to help us?#The [YourShortCivName] have always been friends to our people. The [OtherEmpireName] is gradually destroying our civilization. We plead for any help that you can provide.#The [OtherEmpireName] have grown strong and slowly grinding our civilization to dust. Can you help us?#[OtherEmpireName] is powerful and the war against them is not going well. Is there anything you can do to help?#Please help us! We beg of you. The [OtherEmpireName] are too strong for us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_STARBASE_THREAT_REJECTED">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>It was Human kindness that let you travel through the stars... now it is Human resolution that will wipe your kind from them. Prepare for death.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Then you will die, [YourLeaderName].#Very well. Goodbye, [YourLeaderName]. May your death be as painful as possible.#Do you hear that, [YourLeaderName]? It is the sound of your death. It is the sound of your agony. It is the sound of inevitability.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REJECTION_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I must confess, we Humans have focused too long with warring with only each other. Apparently you are interested in being included now?#Go to hell.#Oh? Well here's a message for you: Kiss. My. Ass.#How do I put this diplomatically? Ah yes, cram it!#I'll see you in hell.#You obviously know little about Humans. We've been killing each other for thousands of years. Do you really think you can intimidate us?#Ha! There's something you should know about us Humans, we have a long history of war. Sadly, we're good at it. Very good at it.#I have skin flakes more impressive than you, [TheirLeaderName].#Explain to me the part where you apparently think we're supposed to be afraid.#We Humans have been killing each other for eons. If you'd like to join our party, go right ahead.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You [TheirShortCivName] are so pathetic... do you really think you can intimidate me?#Bite me, [TheirLeaderName].#Don't make me bite you, [TheirLeaderName].#Don't you have a crappy little empire to go run, [TheirEmpireName]?#Don't waste my time with your dribble.#You're too bold for your own skin... perhaps I can remove it for you.#We [YourShortCivName] don't appreciate being told what to do by YOUR kind.#You're lucky there's a billion light years between us... you'd be torn in half if you tried to intimidate me in person.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REJECTION_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I don't think this is something we can do right now.#This isn't something that is in our best interests.#Sorry, can't help you presently.#Appologies, friend, but we just can't help you at this time.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="B_REJECT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Fail.#I don't think so.#No, I don't think we will be doing that.#(laughs) You don't seem to recognize your position.#That doesn't seem like a very good deal to us.#And this is a good deal HOW?#Tap, tap. Is this Universal Translator on? We must have missed the punch line. Why would we agree to this?#I think not.#This deal is unacceptable.#I would never agree to this.#You been drinking again?#I think not.#This is a joke, correct?#Wouldn't be prudent.#Let me put it like this, not on your life.#Not gonna happen.#Your offer is inadequate.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="B_ACCEPT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Great!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Excellent. I am glad we could come to an agreement.#This is satisfactory.#This agreement will do nicely.#It is done.#Excellent.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SINCERE_THANKS">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You... you want US to have a gift... from YOU?! I... don't know what to say... perhaps change really is possible. I mean, this hardly wipes away thousands of years of oppression... but it goes a long way to mending the bridge between us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We had been slaves so long that we forgot how nice it was to receive something besides a laser-whip to the backside. Thank you much, oh generous [YourLeaderName]... may our races continue to grow closer.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Thank you for your generous gift. I must confess that you Humans know how to show the proper respect. We look forward to improved relations in the future.#Ah, [YourLeaderName], first your gift of hyperdrive, and now this?! I have to say I'm taken aback by your generosity. Let us look forward to a bright future between our people.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You're awfully nice... and I was under the impression you were just pain awful. Here's to a brighter future between the [TheirEmpireName] and the [YourEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Yor">5</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>For being mechanical, you sure have a knack for generosity! May both our races look forward to a prosperous future together.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>[YourLeaderName], your giving nature knows no bounds. If all leaders were as generous of you the galaxy would be a much more inhabitable place. Our future relations with your people are looking up.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Thank you for your generous gift. I must confess that you [YourShortCivName] know how to show the proper respect. We look forward to improved relations in the future.#Your generosity has not gone unnoticed, [YourLeaderName]. Our officials are very impressed in your resolve to keep the bonds of friendship tight between the [YourEmpireName] and our [TheirEmpireName]. May our future relations be as strong as your skills as a diplomat</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>What is this? A gift? It's not actually a disguised bomb, is it? Triggered to go off when I open it? Wow, I never expected such butt-kissing from the [YourEmpireName]... but who cares, I got stuff for free! This makes me like you little more, [YourLeaderName].#You come to bring me presents? Is it my birthday? Or the anniversary of my first kill in combat? This is a very slick bit of brown-nosing, [YourLeaderName], but I can't say it won't go unnoticed.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SINCERE_THANKS_FRIEND">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>I must admit, [YourLeaderName], you have been much too kind to us recently. My high scholars in the field of inter-species relationships have suggested such excellent Diplomacy skills should be rewarded, so I have officially raised our relations with your civilization. May our understanding and appreciation of one another's culture continue to grow.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have been very kind to us lately, [YourLeaderName]. Your excellent skills in diplomacy have convinced our leaders to improve our relations with your civilization.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You sure know how to kiss-butt... no, not literally you weirdo. Due to your excellent skills in Diplomacy, I'm officially improving our relations with your civilization... so don't let anyone say you get nowhere brown-nosing.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_INSINCERE_THANKS">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hold on there, big, green, and charming. I think you've already given us enough gifts.#For a supposedly evil race, you just don't know when to stop giving, do you?#I can't say it's not appreciated, but don't you have civilizations to destroy or something?#If we Humans were as generous as you are, we'd have a lot less stuff.#I don't mind all the gifts, but I hope you don't expect further relation improvements from all this.#I figured you'd be more prone to taking, and here you go with all this giving.#I like the gifts... seriously... and we think you guys are great... but, don't you have someone else you'd rather talk to?#I hope you're not looking to trade these for a backrub or something.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your new-found generosity is welcome, but you can't just sugar coat thousands of years of slavery with a bunch of gifts.#While they are appreciated, but it'll take more than gifts to win back the proper respect of the [TheirShortCivName] people.#The [TheirEmpireName] thanks you for your generosity. Hopefully these gifts show a true change in heart for your people, and aren't some quick-fix to mend poor relations.#[YourLeaderName]... I never would expect this overwhelming generosity from you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The additional gifts are appreciated, but will not effect our relations.#These items will be put to good use.#We calculated an 88.791 to 1 ratio of further gifts from your nation. It appears our calculations were correct.#You'll find that our Artificial Intelligence stops caring about gifts after receiving several in a short period of time. I believe you've reached that point, [YourLeaderName].#Machines are much less prone to flattery as carbon-based organisms. Perhaps you should try, what is the phrase, 'Sucking-Up' to them instead?#Your continued giving is lost on our robotic intellect.#Our stockpile of gifts from the [YourEmpireName] is growing to a illogical size. Do you not have other matters to attend?#If you weren't carbon based I'd be very confused by all these gifts. You're not trying to charm me romantically, are you [YourLeaderName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Ah, more kindness from [YourLeaderName]. Always so giving.#Ah [YourLeaderName], I certainly didn't expect to see you here... again... giving us more gifts... like you did last week.#You're much to giving... perhaps you should share your wealth with a race that may need it more.#I can't say it's a surprise, but thanks for the gift.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, more presents! Thanks!#Man, you just don't stop with the giving!#The free gifts just keep coming, don't they!#You need to keep some of this for yourself, [YourLeaderName]. I mean seriously...</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Your gifts are appreciated but, honestly, enough is enough.#You're pretty desperate for approval, aren't you [YourLeaderName].#OK big spender, I'm not one to turn away free stuff, but you have better things to do with your time?#You're a lonely fella, ain't ya [YourLeaderName]?#Your really don't need to give me any more gifts... wait, what am I saying, I'm an evil race! Give me that free stuff!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SCOFF_AT_BRIBE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Ah, a well timed bribe to halt our forces. Unfortunately the war will go on.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Thanks for the gift, but the war will continue.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>That's very generous, [YourLeaderName], but you can save your possessions... they'll all be mine soon anyways.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GENERIC_THANKS">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We thank you for this generous gift.#Your generosity is greatly appreciated, [YourEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_ATTACKER_DEFINATE_VICTOR">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your military is crushed and your economy can't sustain the effort. Your propaganda to your people becomes more desperate, I can only assume you are here to grovel?#You are defeated. Beg now while you still have a tongue to beg with.#Your life, as it has been, is over. From this point forward, you will service us. Are you prepared to bargain for that future now?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Have our weak Human cousins come here to beg for our mercy? Our mercy may be obtainable for a price. A very high price...#Have you come here to confess the awful truth, that ultimately all Humans are nothing more than cheese-eating surrender monkeys?#We have studied your culture. I think the phrase to use now would be to say, we are most definitely 'kicking your ass'.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Bone-flecked jam. That is the future I see for the Human race if you are not able to grovel your way to peace today.#When we get done with you, you'll wish you had stayed up in the trees of East Africa where you belonged. Grovel now and we might let you live. Maybe.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Yor">5</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The end of the [YourEmpireName] appears at hand. If it makes you feel better, we have found that your kind can be converted to a paste-like substance that makes an excellent lubricant. If you fail, Humanity will live on, sort of.#Our research units are preparing their organ harvesting factories for converting your people to nutrients for our use. They will need to be compensated if you wish to avoid that future.#Sentient organic life forms generate a great deal of energy. We have great plans to grow your kind in vast farms to harvest their energy like a battery. There may be other alternatives if you are willing to pay the right price. But, I doubt it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our people are looking forward to being the slave masters for once.#Your people are pitiful warriors, [YourLeaderName]. Maybe you are better at begging. Let's see how well you do at that.#Pride. It is something that has caused even the best of us to fail. And you are nowhere near 'the best'. Don't let your pride get in the way of your begging today.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your head will look most excellent on a pike in my den. It will go well with my collection. But I am gentle being and am willing to delay that ultimate future if you are willing to pay a high enough price today.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_ATTACKER_WINNING">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>From out vantage point, the war is not going too well for your kind. Are you here to attempt to negotiate 'peace in our time'?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah, so it's our pitiful cousins, the Humans. Soon, there will be no longer be evidence of your existence.#The war is going well... for us. What do you want?#If you are here to grovel, this would be a good time, we may take mercy on you since you are our cousins in some distant way.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You hear that? It is the sound of your death. Do you really think you can defy what is inevitable?#Did you really think your kind had any chance?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The time of your enslavement draws near.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>It would seem your destruction is at hand. Are you here to grovel for mercy?#BOOM. BOOM. BOOM. You hear that? It is the sound of your death knock, knock, knocking on your chamber door.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You are defeated. It is useless to resist. Don't make us destroy you utterly.#Why do you resist... your destruction is the only stable constant in your future, so it should be comforting.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You are at the losing end of this war, [YourLeaderName]. Do not fight what can not be overcome.#I wish you would stop squirming... it makes it harder to bite your head off - figuratively, of course. It's a metaphor for our battling nations. Pretty clever, eh? I just came up with that.#We could crush you quickly, but you continue to put up a fight. Just stop and let your demise come with honor.#Your inability to face an inevitable defeat doesn't come as a surprise. Perhaps you should consider negotiating your way out of this war?#You're the leader of a semi-powerful galactic empire. The lives of billions lie in your decision to continue a failing war... perhaps you'll consider begging for mercy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_ATTACKER_LOSING">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So it would seem we miscalculated when we thought to... persuade your civilization to become one with us. What would you like to discuss?#It appears that this war was a bit of a mistake on our part.#Hah! We were just kidding when we attacked you. Ha ha! See funny right? We really love you guys. Seriously.#Well this isn't going so well. What can we do to make peace?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_DEFENDING_LOSING">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have attacked us and while our military is weak, our ancient civilization has survived much greater challenges.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So you have ruthlessly attacked your peace-loving galactic cousins. I'll not lie to you, you will probably win but we are a brave people. We are prepared to fight to the end if need be.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have attacked us and appear to be winning. So, what do you want from us?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Sigh. We are always the victims. Enslaved, beaten, crushed. Do you take pride in being so ruthless?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Are you interested in ending this war? Do so only if you want true peace and not merely to just attack us again in a few years.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We may not be winning the war, but our people will continue to fight as long as you continue to oppress.#Don't gloat over victory quite yet... the [TheirEmpireName] is far from giving up, even if the outcome looks bleak.#We will continue to fight your evil as long as we can.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_DEFENDING_WINNING">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You foolishly attacked us, [YourLeaderName]. Now you come crawling here for peace I assume?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>It would seem you made a mistake when you ruthlessly attacked us. Now you are here to see if you can persuade us to forgive you?#You attack and now you're losing. Pathetic.#Oh, let me guess, now you want peace?#I may be open to letting you grovel for peace -- though it's going to cost you a body part or two.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_DEFENDING_LOSING_HATE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So, our Human cousins have come to once again ask for peace so that they can rearm, build up and attack again, take a few of our worlds maybe, and then repeat the cycle?#Oh wait, let me guess. You want to make peace. Then you will move your ships into our sectors, build up around our worlds, and then attack us. Once we've weakened you a bit, you'll come back here and ask for peace again? That sound about right?#You Humans are not much like us after all. When we make peace, we mean it. Usually anyway. You, on the other hand, use peace only to let your forces regroup so that you can continue attacks on us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are losing this war. But, make no mistake, we hate your civilization. Your pitiful 'strategy' of attacking us, making peace and then attacking us again disgusts us.#While we are losing, we are willing to fight against you to the bitter end. Your repeated attacks on us after having made peace show your true colors.#Perhaps we are being destroyed. But we have honor, unlike you. We don't make peace only to reload our weapons and attack again.#Ah [YourLeaderName]. So you want to make peace with us after having attacked us. Peace will cost you a great deal more though. Every novice strategist knows the trick of making peace to regroup and then attack again.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_DEFENDING_WINNING_HATE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Carbon-based life forms. They always underestimate the intelligence of artificial life. Will we make peace with you? The price will be very high since you are using predictable strategy #1138 in which opponent merely makes peace to rebuild to attack again and then repeat.#Your limited intelligence has brought you to this state. The groveling you will need to provide to us will be great since we have identified your simple strategy of making peace, attacking, making peace, attacking and so forth.#Let me spell this out, fleshling. We have little interest in peace at this point. We are not interested in having our empire picked off a planet or two at a time and then having you come back to make peace with us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ah yes, the [YourEmpireName] think their pathetic 'strategy' of attacking, taking one of our planets, bribing us with peace, and then building up to attack us again will work? No, you will pay a high price for your lack of vision.#You thought you would just come and make a deal eh? That we would just make peace with you after you have repeatedly attacked us. Ah, the novice strategist thinks we'll just make peace while you organize for another attack and wear us down. Perhaps you should choose a different profession.#Ho ho, [YourEmpireName]. So pathetic. So predictable. Sure, you want us to make peace right? So you can build up and attack us again right? Is that your idea of a winning 'strategy'? Ha!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_NEWWAR_LOSING">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You smug little flesh-creature. You think this war's already won? You have yet to feel the full fury of the [TheirEmpireName].#The Drengin forces may look weaker than yours on paper, but the war is still young, and their passion for war has only started to burn.#We Drengin have been waging war across the galaxy before the Human race even began to crawl. Your war may seem to be going well now, but the tide will soon turn and it's is you that will beg for mercy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The war has just begun, yet you are already coming to make peace?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Peace already?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The war has just begun... what could you possibly want from us?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What, have your 'Give Peace a Chance' protesters have prevailed?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are not terribly interested in war, but we do not trust your sudden desire for diplomacy.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>How ironic that the race that invented hyperdrive is so quick to use it as a weapon. We expected more restraint from you, [YourLeaderName].#The war just started, [YourLeaderName]. Why would you grace my terminal with your war-hungry presence?#To what do I owe the 'honor', [YourLeaderName]. Come to gloat at an early victory?#The war has just begun, [YourLeaderName]. The [TheirEmpireName] may not have the most powerful army, but don't think we'll be a pushover.#Come to give us another technological advancement and then use it to wage war on innocent civilizations?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The war has just started... why the sudden reliance on negotiations?#As far as I can tell you're more interested in fighting than talking.#Ah, the opposition comes to talk. Shake with one hand and ready a dagger in the other, eh, [YourLeaderName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WELCOME_NEWWAR_WINNING">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The Human race may be new to space-travel, but war is sort-of our specialty. And we're confident this war will not end well for you. I can practically taste victory.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The war is fresh and glorious. We are confident of your extermination. You'll be hard pressed to convince us to end it so quickly.#We are winning. You are losing. We, on the other hand, are just getting started...</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The war has only begun. And you are probably doomed. We are interested in territory -- your territory.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You want peace already? If I were you, I would want that too, but we're more interested in trying out some new military hardware.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>It doesn't take much to make you flinch does it?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Humanity is doomed to extinction. The war has only begun as far as we're concerned.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our calculations indicate a favorable outcome in our war against the [YourEmpireName]. You've come to pre-emptively request mercy, perhaps?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The war may be fresh, but your defeat is inevitable. You come to request peace?#How does it feel to be at the losing end of such a young war? It'll take some clever diplomacy to convince us to withdrawal when victory seems so obvious.#So early in the war and you've already come begging for peace? I should have expected this from you, [YourLeaderName].#You're as timid as your forces, [YourLeaderName]. The war has barely begun and you're already sweating.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WANTS_PEACE_REGRETS_ATTACKING">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We don't really like to admit when we're wrong... but MAN did we screw up when we decided to attack you guys. I mean, you're kicking our butts all over the galaxy. So what do you say, [YourLeaderName], what'll it take to put this war behind us?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The Drengin are a war hungry bunch. I know this, and I think it's safe to say you know this. Sometimes, due to warrior instincts fused into our DNA at birth, we act without thinking. Attacking you was one of those times. So how about we end this war, your people can live in peace, and I can take some anger management classes?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You Humans are more powerful than we had expected. Our fleet is shattered. What do we need to do to bring about peace?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Human, this is an awkward moment for us. Remember how we ACCIDENTALLY attacked you awhile back? That is just how our species shows its love of other civilizations. Now that we're kind of, well, dying, we were wondering if you would have mercy on us?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So, how's it going? When my advisors suggested that we attack you, they were kind of expecting that we would crush your civilization. Funny thing is, it turns out that well, crushing is going on but it's you crushing us. So, we were kind of wondering if you would be willing to make peace now?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You carbon-based life forms resist being assimilated far more than we had calculated. We have concluded that we cannot assimilate you by force. Logically, we now wish to end hostilities.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Well you see... it's like this: When we attacked you we were kind of, you know... hoping you'd die. But it seems you're now wiping the galactic floor with us so we were wondering if we could grovel for terms of peace?#Hi. Well, this whole war thing is going a bit differently than planned. You know, the plan where we attack you and you die? Not happening quite like that. Can we do a re-do?#You know, I realize that our mass attack on your people COULD be misinterpreted as hostility, but we really are interested in peace.#My bad. We really didn't mean to attack you. That's just how we show we love ya', baby. Let's call this off.#We're not doing so well with this war thing. Let's end it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WANTS_PEACE_CANT_DEFEND">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You aliens sure can be vicious. You've thoroughly beaten us into submission... let's talk peace before I'm too dead to talk at all.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Don't you think you've made your point? Your military has devastated our space navy and our economy is in desperate shape. What are your terms to make peace?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Surely you don't want to see us destroyed? We are, somehow, related to you by our obvious similarities. Could you please stop destroying us now?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We bow to your superior military power. You have demonstrated your strength. What can we do to bring an end to this war?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our economy is shattered, our empire is coming apart. What have we done to you to deserve this? We only wish peace and friendship with you. Please spare our civilization.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have demonstrated to us quite clearly the superiority of your organic based species in warfare. Let us conclude a peace treaty.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We're beat, OK? You've won. Now what will it take for you to withdrawal your forces? We'll do anything.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WANTS_PEACE_FRIENDLY_INTERVENTION">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>While we loathe you, your friends, the [OtherEmpireName], have been pressuring us to make peace with you. What do we need to do to come to terms?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WANTS_PEACE_WAR_WEARY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Tired... I'm SO tired. Too much war for one lifetime. Please, let's stop wasting each other's time with some never-ending feud and move on with our lives.#I don't want to be the bigger man here, but this is just getting silly. We need to end this war, it's sapping too much of our time and, frankly, I have difficulties remembering why we're fighting in the first place. Let's lay down our weapons and come to a truce.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This war has been going on for a long while. While I am not fond of you, our people are weary of war. Let us come to terms.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>[YourLeaderName]: Our people are weary of this war. What can we do to return to peace?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We're not terribly fond of you, but we have bigger things to rise to and have no more time to deal with your pesky interference.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This war is draining our civilization. While we despise the [YourEmpireName], we also believe it's time to come to terms. Let us end this destructive conflict.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This war is draining precious resources from other vital interests of our empire. We wish to discuss terms to end the war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We're not going to be good friends any time soon, but the time has come to end this war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_WANTS_PEACE_BIGGER_FISH">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We really hate war. We're a peaceful people and this war is costing too much in blood and treasure. Let us come to terms.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Let's end this war now and come to terms. We have a larger plan that does not concern you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We are not fond of you Humans, you interfere with our plans. But right now, our plans do not involve you. Let us come to terms.#You monkeylings are costing us too much blood and treasure. Let us end this destructive conflict.#Listen Earth creature, other matters have come to our attention and our petty struggle with you is a distraction. Let us end the war.#It is true, Human, that in the end only bloody and death will decide the fate for our peoples. But, that end is not now. Your interference is distracting us from our other projects. Let us end this.#When we first came into contact with your kind, we dismissed you as weak and inconsequential. Since then, your rapid expansion has caused us a great deal of grief. This war between us distracts us from our larger goals. In the long term, you cannot stand against us so will not be so generous in treating with you indefinitely. Let us come to terms now and we can divide the galaxy between us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Great deeds are happening at this moment elsewhere on the galactic plane that require our attention. Let us end this feeble conflict.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>It is true we have no love for your kind, but bigger issues are at hand in the galaxy that we must deal with. We are open to a negotiated peace.#We are now open to a negotiated peace. Other concerns have come up that deserve our attention... concerns greater than our petty feud.#This war is costing us too much and you are not worth the effort. Let us come to terms.#This war is interrupting our larger plan for the galaxy, let us come to terms.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_REJECTED_RESPONSE_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have chosen poorly, Human.#So the monkey boy has some back bone. Interesting.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You will suffer for your imprudence.#You won't live to regret this.#So be it. You will be sorry.#You are braver than you look.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_REJECTED_RESPONSE_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Very disappointing.#We had expected more cooperation from our so-called friends.#Your unilateralism is threatening our friendship.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_ACCEPTED_RESPONSE_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We appreciate it.#Thank you, [YourLeaderName].#We are grateful for your gift.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_ACCEPTED_RESPONSE_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have made a wise decision.#You have chosen wisely. You will continue to live... on your knees.#Thank you for donating to our galactic conquest fund.#You may continue to live... for now.#Good work you cheese-eating surrender monkey!#You have chosen to live.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CANT_MAKE_PEACE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We'd love to make peace with them. Unfortunately, they are not willing to do so. Talk to them.#Don't look at me... it's that power hungry [OtherLeaderName] that keeps this war going. Talk to the oppressor, not the victim.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_OFFENSIVE_STARBASE_THREAT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, [YourLeaderName]. Since last scanned, your outpost [StarbaseName] in sector coordinates [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY] has continued to build up it's offensive capabilities. \n With a 86.8236 to 1 possibility ratio that this is a hostile action, we demand that you hand over the indicated outpost immediately. The price for refusal is termination of your species.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I am going to be candid with you, [YourLeaderName]. Your starbase, [StarbaseName], located in sector [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY] is too provocative to stay. It isn't mining a resource. It is building up its offensive weaponry. This is unacceptable to us. Give us the starbase or you will die.#[YourLeaderName]: We are monitoring the construction of [StarbaseName] in sector [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY]. You seem to be behaving as if you are playing some sort of poorly designed strategy simulator. Let us be clear: We are sentient beings who are well aware of the primitive tactic of building up an offensive capability and then attacking. You will hand this starbase over to us. Or, we will destroy you utterly.#Let me be succinct, [YourLeaderName]. We know about the build up of your starbases to an offensive capability for your fleets. For instance, [StarbaseName] in [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY], is near our star system. It is not mining a resource. It is clearly there to build up for an attack.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CULTURAL_STARBASE_THREAT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Let me be frank, [YourLeaderName]. [StarbaseName] in coordinates [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY], is offensive to us. We recognize cultural conquest when we see it. You will hand over this starbase immediately or we will destroy you.#[YourLeaderName], you obviously believe us to be naive. We recognize that [StarbaseName] in sector [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY] exists to try to sway our citizens against us. It will not work. Why? Because you are about to hand over that starbase now or you will be my personal slaveling.#[YourLeaderName], make no mistake, [StarbaseName] located at [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY] is unacceptable. It is a very obvious attempt to try to encourage defections. Since we assume you do not want war, you will hand this starbase over to us. Right. Now.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_STARBASE_CONCERN_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings, friend. We are a little nervous about [StarbaseName] being built in [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY]. We trust you are building this there to help ensure our mutual protection. But, my military advisors are getting a little nervous.#Hello, friend of the [TheirEmpireName]. Our state department has asked me to pass on our concern over the building of [StarbaseName] in sector [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY]. It is gaining a considerable offensive capability.#Greetings as always, friend. I've been asked to pass on to you our nervousness over the increasingly powerful [StarbaseName] being constructed in sector [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY]. While we value our friendship with the [YourEmpireName], we are going to maintain a close eye on this starbase.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_STARBASE_CONCERN_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are concerned about the starbase you are building in sector [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY]. It is not mining any resource, but instead seems to be gaining a significant offensive capability. We ask that you cease this. Disbanding it would be a good first step.#The starbase known as [StarbaseName], located in sector [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY], is acquiring a significant offensive capability. We ask that you cease this construction immediately.#When I was younger, I used to play strategy entertainment consoles. In these, 'games', as you call them, I would first build up my forces around the unsuspecting computerized players. Then I would attack. The computerized players were unaware of this. Human, we are not computerized players. We are a proud and ancient sentient civilization. [StarbaseName], in sector [StarbaseX], [StarbaseY], is a threat to us. We ask that you disband this starbase immediately.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REPLY_STARBASE_CONCERN">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>No need to be concerned.#We have galactic defense obligations to meet.#When you're as powerful as we are, you can't be too careful.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You can whine all you want, but there's not much you can do about it.#If we wanted to destroy you, you'd know it.#So what are you going to do? Cry? Go ahead, squirt out a few.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REPLY_STARBASE_CONCERN_STRONGER_LOWDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Well too bad.#Tough.#We're big. We're tough. Whatcha going to do about it?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REPLY_STARBASE_CONCERN_WEAKER_LOWDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Oh, those little old things? They're for a... ummm... movie we're making.#We just like to build up our starbases. It's a bit of a hobby.#Gotta keep those defense contractors busy you know.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REPLY_STARBASE_HIGHDIP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You can trust us, [TheirLeaderName]. The starbase in question is for defensive purposes only... we can both understand the threat of less civilized nations.#We're just building it for defensive purposes, [TheirEmpireName]. There is no reason for the [TheirEmpireName] to be worried about [StarbaseName].#It's nothing to be worried about, [TheirLeaderName]. We have nothing to gain from threatening the [TheirEmpireName] with some vole-infested old starbase!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_UNDERSTAND_INFO">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Understood.#I will inform my advisors.#Thank you for this useful information.#I appreciate being kept in the loop.#Many thanks, [TheirLeaderName]. Please let us know if you learn anything further.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_NO_EXCHANGE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Just let us know if you ever remember what you came to say.#Perhaps your transmission was lost. Try sending that again.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>What? Nothing came through. Try sending again.#Try filling your message queue before pressing the send button.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Nothing came through. Thanks for wasting my valuable time.#Next time how about sending something, moron.#I know the big and shiny SEND button is very tempting to press, but try not to until you've actually ENTERED a message.#You're not the brightest bulb, are you [YourLeaderName]? Try sending a message next time.#You didn't send anything. Idiots like you are why I prefer to wipe out civilizations opposed to talk things through.#Don't say you want to talk and just send over empty messages. You may have time to waste, but I do not.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_NO_EXCHANGE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Oh, sorry about that.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Oops.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>I'm [YourLeaderName] - I'll press the Send button whenever I want.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_THREAT_RESPONSE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We don't take kindly to threats, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_REJECT_TOO_SOON">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Does the [YourEmpireName] think of us as their own private bank that they can simply come to constantly to get a withdrawal?#Did you not recently come to us asking for tribute? We do not wish to fight you but we will not bankrupt ourselves to serve you.#It would not be in our best interests to continually supply the [YourShortCivName] war machine with revenue. Even though we've given you gifts in the past, it is not something we wish to continually do.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_REJECT_WEAKER">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Though we admire your military might, our people will not give in to your extortion!#Our civilization was thriving while you were still hunting and gathering. You may be stronger than us now in some ways, but you are not nearly powerful enough for us to give in to your demands.#I think not, [YourLeaderName]. While some say that your power is destined to rule the galaxy, we will resist aiding you in that quest while we are able.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_REJECT_STRONGER">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This must be some sort of joke. Your military power is not sufficient to carry out any sort of threats as far as we're concerned.#I don't think so.#We laugh at your threats. We have no use for you or your pitiful demands.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_REJECT_EQUAL">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So it has come to this. The Humans gave the galaxy Hyperdrive technology as a gesture of peace but now that you have tasted power you demand tribute. Very well. We shall give you tribute, but beware Human, the price may be high in the long-run.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your military is in no position to carry out threats. While we admire your potential military power, it is just that, potential.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_ACCEPT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>If it is what you demand.#We are in no position to question you, [YourLeaderName]... so we will do as requested.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>It appears we have no alternative but to do as you... request.#Fine. We didn't want those things anyway!#Very well. But we will not forget your threats.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Using your power to blackmail us is something we can truly appreciate. However, your time to die will come, [YourLeaderName].#I should have seen this coming, you slimy dog. Your demands will be met this time, but the next time you threaten [TheirLeaderName], you'll be met with death.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_ACCEPT_PLAYER_EVIL">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>I would expect nothing less than threats from the vile [YourLeaderName].#We will do as you demand. But know this, one day the good civilizations of the galaxy will stand up to you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your vile threats may have worked today, but those races that live in your evil shadow will eventually take the [YourEmpireName] down.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Using your power to blackmail us is something we can appreciate. However, your time to die will come. Remember those words. I wouldn't bother putting anymore money away for retirement, either.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_ACCEPT_PLAYER_GOOD">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>So is this the type of behavior one can expect to see from the so-called honorable [YourEmpireName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I would expect this out of the others, but I thought you were one of the good guys! You can have as you've demanded, but I expected better of you, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Wow, looks like you've been studying our race closely, eh [YourLeaderName]. I couldn't have done it better myself: using your might to force demands down my throat... genius! Don't get me wrong, you will eventually die, a slow painful death, by my hand, but for now enjoy your spoils of victory, you clever weasel.#The chameleon shows his true colors. For a peace loving race you sure know how to threaten the weak, [YourLeaderName]. You can have as you've demanded, but rest assured that I'll be back to reclaim them... at the expense of your life.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TRIBUTE_DEMAND_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Friend, our peace keeping efforts throughout the galaxy are expensive. We need you to help contribute to this by transferring [CashValue] bc from your treasury to ours.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TRIBUTE_DEMAND_TECH_INSTEAD">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your civilization is too poor to pay us enough to allow you to continue to exist. Therefore we ask that you hand over some of your technology. In exchange, we will let you live.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TRIBUTE_DEMAND_PLANET_INSTEAD">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Since we must be related anyway, we are sure you won't mind handing over one of your planets to your betters. We'll take good care of it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your civilization is utterly worthless. We will allow you to take up valuable space in our galaxy if you hand over one of your planets.#Your civilization is pathetic... no cash to give, no techs to offer. We will allow your empire to continue its feeble existence if you hand over one of your planets. Pray that I don't have any more relatives who need a vacation home.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TRIBUTE_DEMAND_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>[YourLeaderName]: While many of our people want to conquer you and harvest your species for its organs (especially its delicious skin) I am a kinder, gentler being and would be satisfied with merely [CashValue] bc.#We are debating whether it is best to enslave your kind or exterminate you. If you would like to delay our final decision, provide us with [CashValue] bc now.#Let's be clear: give us stuff or you will die.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>[CashValue] bc. That's how many billions of credits I will need from you to convince our military to not exterminate your civilization. And I'll be needing that today. In cash.#We don't see much use for your civilization other than as a revenue source. Give us [CashValue] bc if you wish to continue existing.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We have heard you Humans have a saying. That it is better to die on your feet than live on your knees. If you wish to live you will do so on your knees and start by paying us [CashValue] bc in tribute.#We have laid claim over some of the territory you now occupy. Therefore we require some rent to continue utilizing the planets you're on. Hand over [CashValue] bc if you wish to live.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your pathetic race has no business being out here in space. The fact that your kind created the Hyperdrive technology was clearly a fluke. You will pay us tribute of [CashValue] bc if you wish to continue to live.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your civilization is proof that biological life forms are inferior. Still, we believe you do generate some level of GDP and hence can afford to pay us [CashValue] bc in order to fund our expansion.#Fleshling, we have no use for carbon-based life forms such as you. Transfer [CashValue] bc of your treasury to us or face the consequences.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your civilization makes us laugh. If you would like to continue to exist, transmit [CashValue] bc to us immediately.#Pay us [CashValue] bc in tribute now if you wish to live as an independent empire.#Your military power is inadequate to defend yourselves in this hostile galaxy. We suggest you provide us with [CashValue] bc so that we can protect you -- from us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TEAM_UP_AGAINST_GOOD_CIV">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are both evil. We understand that. But the [OtherEmpireName] ... well they are not evil. And that's a problem for us. They are a threat to our torture-loving ways. We must act together to ensure that the galaxy is filled with misery and pain as it should be.#We both seem to believe that evil shall ultimately triumph in the galaxy. As it should be. We must work together to crush opposition which means that the [OtherEmpireName] must be destroyed eventually. For now, we must act covertly but let us work towards that eventuality.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TEAM_UP_AGAINST_EVIL_CIV">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The [OtherEmpireName] are covering the galaxy in a reign of sickness and darkness. The time to formally join together is not at hand. But, we must work together covertly to oppose them. Make no mistake, they will crush us separately if we do not resist.#A new darkness is slowly covering the galaxy. I give that darkness a name: the [OtherEmpireName]. We must work together in secret to ensure the survival of our civilizations.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TEAM_UP_AGAINST_CIV">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Have you been keeping an eye on the [OtherEmpireName]? Their power is growing. We must begin to formulate a plan to stop them.#We are concerned by the growing dominance of the [OtherEmpireName]. If things do not change, we fear that they will come to dominate the galaxy.#The [OtherEmpireName] threat is growing. I suggest we quietly supply arms and money to any who are actively at war with them. Hopefully we can help loosen their grip on the considerable number of galactic resources they control.#The influence of the [OtherEmpireName] is growing very strong. They build starbases that intentionally magnify their cultural influence. If you do not wish to become an appendage of their empire, I suggest you work with us to resist their domination.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SUCK_UP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We love you. I mean, we really love you. Please have some stuff.#We admire your power and wish to offer you this gift in recognition of your greatness and peaceful nature!#Your benevolence has won the admiration of our people and we would like to present you with this token of our good will towards your wonderful culture.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TRADE_TECH">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We need '[YourTechnology]'... and you need '[TheirTechnology]'. It only makes sense for us to trade these two techs for the good of our nations.#You remember Hyperdrive? How we were nice enough to just GIVE that to you? Well, we have another technological BREAKTHROUGH we think you might be interested in, but this time we were hoping for a more 'equal' trade: '[YourTechnology]' for '[TheirTechnology]'.#'[YourTechnology]' for '[TheirTechnology]'... you know it's a good deal, [YourLeaderName]! Just click Accept and we can both reap the benefits of our new technology.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are not proud to admit it, but our scientists have yet to make a breakthrough in a field you seem to have excelled in. Would you be open to trading '[YourTechnology]' for '[TheirTechnology]'?#The [TheirShortCivName] have always been better warriors than scientists, [YourLeaderName]. Your kind seem to have researched a technology that we have failed to explore. What do you say... your '[YourTechnology]' for our [TheirTechnology]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have advanced in a field that we have not yet been able to pursue. Would you share your knowledge of '[YourTechnology]' for ours of '[TheirTechnology]'?#There is research that you've done in a field called '[YourTechnology]'. We are willing to share our knowledge of '[TheirTechnology]' for this technology.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Korx">6</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I have other offers on the table, but I just wanted to see if you wanted it first, [YourLeaderName]. To your most worthy race, the [TheirEmpireName] is willing to trade their knowledge of [TheirTechnology] for yours of [YourTechnology]. And please respond quickly... like I said, I have other buyers are waiting.#Greetings, [YourLeaderName]! I'm here to let you know that the ground-breaking '[TheirTechnology]' can be yours today! All I would need is a small trade to make this technology yours... perhaps your '[YourTechnology]'?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Thalan">8</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetingssss! I wasss hoping to exchange technologies with you today, [YourLeaderName]. How doesss a trade of '[YourTechnology]' for '[TheirTechnology]' ssssound to you?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Iconian">9</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Yor">5</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>How ironic that the beings that we created have gone to develop technologiessss that even our own scientists have yet to uncover. We are here to offer your knowledge of [YourTechnology] for ours of [TheirTechnology].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Iconian">9</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We, the [TheirEmpireName], have decided to grace you with a grand opportunity. We are offering our ground-breaking [TheirTechnology], and all we ask is your practically worthless [YourTechnology]. It's a hard deal to refuse, we know.#The gracious [TheirEmpireName] wishes to extend an agreement with you regarding some technologies. If you would agree to it, we would like to exchange our [TheirTechnology] for your [YourTechnology]. Is this acceptable?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hello, [YourLeaderName]. We are interested in trading technology with you: your '[YourTechnology]' for our '[TheirTechnology]'. Is this deal acceptable?#Greetings. We have some interest in your technology. Would a trade of '[YourTechnology]' for '[TheirTechnology]' be acceptable?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_GROVEL_RELATIONS_OK">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are always willing to help out our friends.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_GROVEL_RELATIONS_LOW">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>I guess we don't have much choice in the matter. We have done as you asked.#Okay, here you go. Please don't hurt us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We'll do what you ask, just don't hurt us.#Very well, we will do as you want.#It is done. You will find that we are excellent collaborators.#Okay, no need to be rude.#We'll do what you want.#As you wish.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You may have gotten what you want this time, but we will feast on your entrails one day.#We'll give you what you demand but one day, we'll shove that tribute right down your throat.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REPLY_HELP_LOST_CAUSE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>It pains me to see you so helpless when they're faced with mortality. Alas, even with all our help I fear your empire would be doomed. I'm sorry, old friend.#We will try and get help out to your forces, but I fear your cause may be lost. The [OtherEmpireName] is just too powerful... I'm sorry.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Don't take this badly, but your cause is lost.#Helping you would be a waste of resources, I'm afraid. You should let your people be aware that the end is near. I'll see if there's anything we can do to delay the inevitable.#How can I put this delicately? You're probably doomed.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Why would we help you? Your empire is S C R E W E D!#And jump on the sinking ship known as the [TheirEmpireName]?! Doubtful.#Stop your whining and face death with honor... and while your at it, how about you give us some free stuff to remember you by... I'd hate to see it all go to the [OtherEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REPLY_HELP">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We will do our best to muster up the forces to help you, my friend.# I will seek council on the matter and try my best to get help to you as soon as possible. Hang in there, my friend.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Let me see if there's anything we can do to help you.#I will consult with my advisors as to whether we can help.#If we can help, we will.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We're fighting our own wars, thank you very much. But, if we can spare a fighter or two, perhaps we'll send it your way.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REPLY_GAVE_INFO">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Thanks for the information.#Believe me, we know this.#We're doing our part.#We are monitoring the situation.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>I believe it... I haven't trusted [OtherLeaderName] since the day we crossed paths.#I KNEW that [OtherLeaderName] was up to no good!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_REPLY_GAVE_INFO_ON_FRIEND">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Thanks, [YourLeaderName], but we are close friends with the [OtherEmpireName] and trust them entirely. Perhaps your informer was mistaken?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Perhaps, but [OtherLeaderName] is also our friend.#We have good relations with them, but we'll take your message under advisement.#They are our friends, but we will heed your warning.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Grrr... those slimy, two-faced rats! I knew something was up with [OtherLeaderName]. We'll be on the lookout for more of their foul ways.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CONCERN_TOO_MUCH_DEBT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We have significant debt. Taking on more is not an option.#Woah, woah, woah! Hold on there, big trader. We can't possible make that deal... our debt is already a problem... this offer would cripple us!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CONCERN_THEYRE_TOO_STRONG">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>I'm afraid our military just isn't strong enough to wage an effective war against [OtherLeaderName]'s forces. I apologize for the miscommunication on the matter.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Their military power is just too strong. Forget it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You think I'm crazy?! Not even I'm blood-thirsty enough to pick a fight with the [OtherEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CONCERN_TRANSPORTS_IN_AREA">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Sorry, I've been advised to keep ships in orbit in those areas due to an increase in foreign Transport activity. Once the transports are out of range, I'll be open to trading those vessels.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Uh, no, we're not going to trade ships with you when you have so many Transports full of troops near us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Oh, [YourLeaderName], you clever dog. Trying to pull my ships out of orbit so you can bring in your Transports for an easy kill? I don't think so, my friend.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="DECLARE_WAR_ON_EVIL_PLAYER">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Prepare to die, Human. We declare war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This war is ON and you must die.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Well fleshling, you know what we think of you? We think you Humans are good. In fact, we think you're delicious. For that reason, we are going to conquer you now. Prepare for your doom. And we have studied your evil behavior throughout the galaxy. Did you really think you could simply replace the rightful rulers of the galaxy - us - with your own brand of cruelty?#We've been studying Earth for some time, as you know. You Humans have thwarted us time and time again and now, here at this time, we shall put our might up against yours.#Earth will suffer greatly for your interference. And any mercy we shall have on you, which shall be little, owes only to the fact that it was, somehow, you Humans that first discovered Hyperdrive technology. Through hyperdrive, we now have the means to bring our death furnaces to you to wipe your pathetic species.#In the end, any colonies of Humans will be exterminated. But we will keep Earth special. The Humans there shall be slavelings to do as we command.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>The Drengi are a filthy, evil, race that must be wiped out. Now, the tables are turned, Drengin scum. Now we shall do to you as you once did to us. Long ago the Ur-Quan Hierarchy occupied our world. That was in the time before Hyperdrive. Now, with Hyperdrive, we can send reinforcements to ensure that we grind your civilization into dust!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The Drengi are a filthy, evil, race that must be wiped out. Now, the tables are turned, Drengin scum. Now we shall do to you as you once did to us. Long ago the Ur-Quan Hierarchy occupied our world. That was in the time before Hyperdrive. Now, with Hyperdrive, we can send reinforcements to ensure that we grind your civilization into dust!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The Drengi are a filthy, evil, race that must be wiped out. Now, the tables are turned, Drengin scum. Now we shall do to you as you once did to us. Long ago the Ur-Quan Hierarchy occupied our world. That was in the time before Hyperdrive. Now, with Hyperdrive, we can send reinforcements to ensure that we grind your civilization into dust!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Well Human, your vile behavior across the galaxy has given us no choice but to purge you from existence. Your evil will be ended once and for all.#We have studied your planet well, Earth creature. And your history explains much as to why you are such brutal and sadistic creatures.#Prepare to be destroyed.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>It is time for your people to become one with us. This, sadly, will cut your time short on your petty evil but we will integrate you into our society as best we can. You, however, will not survive.#Humans have proven time and time again how evil you really are through your actions. Now we will visit upon you the kind of pain you have visited upon others.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Well monkey boy, we can appreciate your tendency to do cruel and horrible things to other creatures. We do the same thing to fleshlings everywhere. But, now it is your turn to suffer a similar fate. No hard feelings?#When we get to your home planet, we will have plenty of time to look through your continents to see what the best way to exterminate your people without damaging the planet too much.#But, one thing will be certain: when we are done with you, the galaxy will be free of creatures of your kind.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Your civilization is simply too evil to be allowed to continue. Prepare to die.#We consider it our mission to help rid the galaxy of evil. Your civilization fits that description nicely and therefore your planets will be rid of your presence soon enough... prepare to die.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Nothing personal, but the time has come to remove you from the galaxy. But to be honest, I doubt few will be sorry to see your evil civilization go away.#For the good of all living things, we have decided your empire must be destroyed.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The time for war has come. Prepare for your doom. We have learned much from your evil ways and plan to use them -- on you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="DECLARE_WAR_ON_PLAYER">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We have given the galaxy the gift of Hyperdrive technology, but feel you have abused the great powers the technology allows, so now we give a second gift... your race's swift and absolute termination.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Prepare to die, Humans.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Prepare to die, Humans.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You have interfered with our plans for the last time, Human. Enough of these games, we shall crush you and your civilization.#The fact you guys built Las Vegas alone justifies your extermination. The fact you keep getting in our way demonstrates you need to die.#Diet soda? Do you really think a species that could invent that could be allowed to live? Prepare for your doom.#In the end, any colonies of Humans will be exterminated. But we will keep Earth special. The Humans there shall be slavelings to do as we command.#All your base are belong to us.#You Humans will soon be our slavelings. Prepare to die.#Time to die, Human!#It is time. We always knew that this would end in war. Now we shall destroy you.#I've got a song for you, Human. It goes like this: 'This land is my land and now so is your land'. Prepare to die.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Torian">4</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>It's sad that your people have come this far, but unfortunately they still haven't been able to properly adjust to being a major player in the galaxy. The strong will rise to the top, while the weak stumble and die. We're just speeding along the process... we'd hate for the [YourEmpireName] to suffer through an existence of mediocracy. Prepare for your extermination.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your people will soon be under our rule once again, [YourLeaderName]. Face your doom.#OK, you've had your fun as a free nation. Now it is time for us to round all the Torians up for a second age of enslavement. We assume you won't come peacefully, so prepare for the full fury of the Drengin Army.#You filthy Torian scum... you thought you could get away from our iron grasp, but now the mighty Drengin Army is at your doorstep. Prepare to once again become our slavelings.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our Death Furnaces don't power themselves you know. We've calculated that it'll be easier to fuel them with your carcasses than to mine the ore necessary to power them.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Altarian">2</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>You Humans are so like us. And your military is so weak that it is inevitable that you will be conquered by someone. Therefore, we reason, it is better to be conquered by us than by someone else. Please do not resist as we will try to make your... eh... liberation as painless as possible.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Prepare to be destroyed.#We have much in common with you. And soon, your planets will be something we have in common. Prepare to become part of our Empire.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You Humans disgust us. You are copies of us that we can no longer tolerate.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Prepare for your destruction, Human.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Ever since we first came in contact with you around 100 of your years ago, we have had to decide whether we should conquer you or work with you. We have decided that the balance of power in the galaxy has shifted and that the time to conquer you has come.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Now we can put an end to you Humans once and for all.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Arcean">3</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are a proud and powerful civilization. As such, we need subject worlds to worship us. Given your pitiful lack of military power, we have decided to educate you in matters of warfare from the losers' perspective. Prepare to die.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>The tables are turned, Drengin scum. Now we shall do to you as you once did to us. Long ago the Ur-Quan Hierarchy occupied our world. That was in the time before Hyperdrive. Now, with Hyperdrive, we can send reinforcements to ensure that we grind your civilization into dust!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The tables are turned, Drengin scum. Now we shall do to you as you once did to us. Long ago the Ur-Quan Hierarchy occupied our world. That was in the time before Hyperdrive. Now, with Hyperdrive, we can send reinforcements to ensure that we grind your civilization into dust!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The tables are turned, Drengin scum. Now we shall do to you as you once did to us. Long ago the Ur-Quan Hierarchy occupied our world. That was in the time before Hyperdrive. Now, with Hyperdrive, we can send reinforcements to ensure that we grind your civilization into dust!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Torian">4</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Long ago we were enslaved by the Ur-Quan Hierarchy. In time, we were able to fight them off. This means when we conquer you, we know how to keep you from ever being free again.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The time of purification has arrived. We, who were once slaves of the Ur-Quan Hierarchy, can now cleanse the galaxy under our rule.#Our civilization was once enslaved but we broke free! This may seem like words of inspiration but what we actually mean by that is that we know how to prevent you from ever being free again. Do not resist, it will only make things harder for you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Our dealings with the Ur-Quan Hierarchy have taught us much. One thing that it has taught us is that we cannot stand other sentient beings. So... you must be exterminated.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our civilization detests carbon-based life forms such as your own. Therefore we will conquer your species and then exterminate you all. Nothing personal. End of line.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Okay Human, here's the thing, your so-called "amusement parks" are really fun. In fact, they're so fun that we want them for our own. So, well, how do I put this delicately, we are going to have us as permanent guests very soon. Prepare for war.#I regret to inform you that we have decided to annex your territory. Sound the horns or milk the goats or whatever it is you people do, but prepare for war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>So Human, we meet again for the first time for the last time. But before you die, there is something you must know. I am your father's, brother's cousin's former roommate. Which means you are about to become nothing at all...#I will avoid using pointless cliches to explain this so I will be brief: prepare to die!#Our people need more room in this galaxy and that room happens to be occupied by you. Consider this your eviction notice.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We've heard Human flesh tastes excellent. We are about to find out. Prepare to die!#The time of your extermination is at hand. But fear not, we shall keep a few specimens of Human on hand in our zoos for our amusement.#Time to die, Earther!#So long, farewell, death is knocking at your door. And we won't be stopped by your puny fleet. The Human race is about to go extinct.#We shall crush your civilization and enslave your pathetic people, Human.#Resistance is futile, Earther. It is the end of the world as you know it. And, I feel fine about that...#I am here to inform you that you are dead. You may not feel dead but soon, you will wish you were. Once we conquer all the Human worlds, we will put you to work.#Earth is doomed and so are you. All of Earth's major cities shall be wiped out except for the city of Plymouth, Michigan which we shall use as a sanctuary to display what's left of the Human race.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We are ever so sorry to have to do this but the territory you currently... well... exist on is actually needed by our people. We will try to make this as painless as possible but, in the end, your civilization must come to an end. Prepare for your end.#We need new land to build overpriced, sub-standard vacation homes with a view of a lake. Your land will do nicely.#It is time to bring our enlightened ideals to your people. Surrender now if you know what's best for you.#Your territory shall become ours.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The time for war has arrived. Prepare to be destroyed.#Our disgust of the [YourEmpireName] can be contained no more... you and your kind will die.#War is only acceptable if used as a last resort between nations, but in your case, we'll make an exception. Prepare for death.#The [YourEmpireName] is a stain on the fabric of a strong galaxy... prepare to be eradicated.#We're sorry to inform you, but we have decided we need more breathing room. Prepare to die.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We shall soon see who is the stronger -- you or us. We shall grind your civilization into the dust. We declare war!#We're hungry and you are coming to dinner -- as the main course. Prepare for death.#Time to die.#The galaxy is too small for the two of us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_REJECT_FRIENDS">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Carbon-based life forms spend too much time worrying about material items. We deny this request.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>My apologies, but we are unable to give you those items at the moment. Perhaps some other time.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I'm sorry. We can't help you today.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>I have my own concerns at the moment, [YourLeaderName]. I don't have time to be giving handouts.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="B_ASK_FOR_SUPPLIES">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We request, oh generous [YourLeaderName], the donation of certain supplies to our humble nation:#Greetings, fellow space traveler. We request the following items from your little empire... if you have them, of course!:#In our effort to bring peace to the galaxy, we must ask you to donate selflessly to our cause.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Greetings. Could the [TheirEmpireName] give some supplies to help us through a tough time?:#I know we all need supplies, but I'd really be appreciated if you could give us a hand and donate the following:</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>It pains me to admit it, but we need some supplies. Could you help an evil brother out?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CONCERN_NO_WEAPON_TRADE_FRIENDLY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Sorry, friend, but my advisors just doesn't feel comfortable handing weapon technology over to you when the [YourShortCivName] military is already so powerful.Honestly, if it was up to me you could have them... we're pals, I know you're trustworthy... but I have to run an honest government here, and my comrades feel strongly about declining the offer. I'm sorry.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This is a fine offer, but my military advisors insist that handing over such powerful Weapons technology to the already powerful [YourEmpireName] is not in the best interest of the [TheirShortCivName] people.My apologies, [YourLeaderName], but we can't accept the trade as long as those technologies are included.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>As much as I like that offer, my overbearing advisors keep insisting that trading Weapon technologies over to the [YourEmpireName] wouldn't be prudent.I don't think it matters... I know how the warriors' instinct works, and you [YourLeaderName] do NOT have a warriors' instinct, but unfortunately I have to say no.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CONCERN_NO_WEAPON_TRADE_DISTRUST">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Just because we are a peaceful race does not make us naive. You are building up a dangerous army, [YourLeaderName], and we will not willingly make this trade with you requesting such powerful Weapon technologies. The mere suggestion insults our intelligence.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I can't believe you, [YourLeaderName]. Asking for technologies to build up your already staggering army, when, for all I know, you could be planning an all-out assault my people? No, no, no, [YourLeaderName]. You can take your 'offer' and shove it... we're through here.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Ha! Trying the old 'Bait and Switch' on me, eh? You come to trade for Weapons technologies, then use those same technologies to wage war against my empire?!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_REJECT_NO_WEAPON_DEMAND_FRIENDLY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>My apologies, but as much as you may need these items, I don't think it'd be in the [TheirShortCivName] peoples' best interest to hand over such powerful Weapons technology to the already overwhelming [YourShortCivName] army. May our friendship continue, despite my inability to do as you've requested.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Sorry, [YourLeaderName], but my military advisors have put up the big 'red flag' when it comes to handing over that Weapon technology to the most powerful military in the galaxy. No offense, friend, but we just can't give you those items.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Ha! Your request is a bold one, [YourLeaderName], but I have a hard time justifying just GIVING those Weapons technologies to most powerful army around. You should enjoy being on top, and as flattered as I am by your envy, I have to decline this request.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_REJECT_NO_WEAPON_DEMAND_HOSTILE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We will not willingly hand over technologies that will strengthen the already repulsive [TheirShortCivName] army. Even if it brings down your wrath, handing over those technologies is too dangerous for us to agree to.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You arrogant twit... how dare you try and blackmail us for weapons that you'll probably just use to wage war on the [TheirEmpireName]? Your army may be strong, but one day you will be put in your place.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>It's just not enough for you to have the most powerful fleet around, eh [YourLeaderName]? But now, you have the nerve to demand more Weapons technology for your growing military machine?! May your blind greed and arrogance lead you to a slow, painful death.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="B_ACCEPT_REQUEST_FOR_SUPPLIES">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your request has been approved.#We will assist you by donating the requested items.#We will comply with your request.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We can help you this time, friend.#Certainly, friend. The items you've requested will be provided.#How can I turn my back on my pal [YourLeaderName]!#Of course... just let us know if there's anything else you need!#Sure, and if we need something down the road perhaps you can return the favor?#Anything to help our friends in the [YourEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>No problem... just don't make a habit of it asking for handouts.#Of course the [TheirEmpireName] will help out if you're that strapped for supplies.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Nobody likes a beggar, [YourLeaderName]. But since you're our friends, my advisors say we should help you out. Your request for supplies has been approved.#Here you go, [YourLeaderName]... but just remember, you owe us!#Sure, we can help you out... and I'll just write up a little IOU to remind me that you owe us big, [YourLeaderName].#The [TheirEmpireName] never turns away from a chance to rack up debts from others. The requested items are yours, [YourLeaderName]. We'll talk later...</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BLACKMAIL_REJECT_FRIENDS_TOO_SOON">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>I'm sorry, but didn't we just give you supplies?#What did you do with the items we just gave you? That wasn't enough?#Our friendship should be based on more than me giving and you taking.#Perhaps you would gain more by returning the kindness we just showed you, instead of requesting more handouts? Speaking of which, are you ever planning to return my power-sander?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>I just gave you a bunch of stuff... now you want more?#No, I'm sorry... No more handouts.#We will help out on occasion, but don't confuse our generosity for stupidity, 'friend'.#Seriously, we're not the 'First Galactic Bank of [YourLeaderName]'.#Please take your requests elsewhere.#'Me', 'Me', 'Me'. You're quite needy, aren't you, [YourLeaderName]?#Nobody likes a mooch, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Your begging grows old, [YourLeaderName].#Sounds like someone needs to learn how to stand on their own two feet.#What about my needs? How about you give ME something? That sounds like more fun.#Your requests are making my blood start to boil, [YourLeaderName].#No, you can't have that.#Go away... I'm sick of your begging.#Get off your knees and act like a true leader. And NO, you can't have that stuff.#NO! Go away, man... it's getting old!#NO you can't have more of my stuff.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CONCERN_USELESS_TECHS_FRIENDLY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We consider ourselves a very generous people, but for us to trade for [UsefulTechName], along with it's preceding techs, would be quite silly. I mean, who needs any of the older technology when you'd have the latest, greatest version? I'm sorry, [YourLeaderName], but we can't agree to this deal.#So, I noticed you put in a bunch of older techs in the same path as the newer one. Why exactly would we need that junk when you're planning to trade [UsefulTechName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>As tempting as your offer is, it just doesn't make sense for us to trade for [UsefulTechName] along with all its worthless preceding techs. Once we have that more powerful technology, the others are fairly useless; wouldn't you agree [YourLeaderName]?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>I don't know what we would use all those other techs for when we'd already have [UsefulTechName]. That deal seems a bit shady, [YourLeaderName] and we KNOW a shady deal when we see it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CONCERN_USELESS_TECHS_HOSTILE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We're not fools, [YourLeaderName]. You try to fluff up the deal with the worthless prerequisites to the technology '[UsefulTechName]', then pass it off like you're going us a favor? We may be a kind people, but kindness does not equate to stupidity.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>No. I'm sorry but trading for [UsefulTechName], along with it's prerequisite techs, would be VERY stupid on our part... and we're just not that stupid. Try a bit harder, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Our fleets have no use for those other techs if we were to receive the more powerful [UsefulTechName] in the trade. Your offer disgusts me, [YourLeaderName]. I hope one day your cocky diplomacy tricks lead you to an early grave.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TRADE_UPDATE_POSITIVE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>This is a fair trade.#The items on both side of the trade equal out.#Calculations indicate this is a good trade.#My items would be worth your items in this dealing, flesh creature.#[YourLeaderName], so far your request is a fair one.#We could agree to this barter.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>I like what I see.#A fairly positive trade, it should seem.#I approve thus far.#So far, so good.#Looks acceptable.#Not bad.#Go on.#Very nice.#Keep going.#This I would go for.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>That seems to be an acceptable proposal.#An interesting proposal, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Not too shabby, [YourLeaderName]. I could go for that!#I've seen worse deals.#You're quite the shrewd negotiator, [YourLeaderName].#Can't say I wouldn't approve of this deal.#A decent trade.#The trade seems fair so far.#Very nice.#Keep it up.#I would accept this.#This looks good to me, [YourLeaderName].#This would be accepted by my government, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_TRADE_UPDATE_NO_EXCHANGE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>. . .</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hmmm...</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CRY_FOR_HELP_REJECTED">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You have sent us to our doom. I hope you can survive when [OtherEmpireName] comes for you.#Very well, we shall remember this.#In time, they will come for you.#We are the only thing keeping them from going after you. You must know this.#I hope you can sleep at night.#May the gods curse you.#In time, the [OtherEmpireName] will consume you.#You're next... You know that, right?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CRY_FOR_HELP_UPDATE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We would be honored to accept your aid.#Thank you!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_CRY_FOR_HELP_ACCEPTED">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You are my hero, [YourLeaderName]!#We shall sing songs in your name.#You are our champion!#May all the hamsters of your world dance the dance of joy!#Thank you! I take back all the mean things I said about you.#Oh joy! I take back all the things I've said about your spouse.#May your body odor become a musk for the opposite sex of your kind.#I promise to send you a Kalvanian lizard eye for your birthday!#I love you man!#You are the wind beneath my wings!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="DECLARE_WAR_TO_DEFEND_FRIEND">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>The galaxy is not a friendly place at the moment and you are at war with our friend. Nothing personal, but I'm afraid we're going to have to... take care of you.#It's a shame you are at war with our friend... We have no choice but to side with them in their war against you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We have nothing personal against you, but you are at war with a friend of ours. Which... is disruptive to our economy. I'm afraid you're going to have to be eliminated.#Your war with our friend is causing damage to our economy. Our people demand stability and we feel you are the obstacle to that stability. Therefore... we will have to wipe you out.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Your war with our friend may not be your fault. But, we don't really care because it is inconveniencing us. Therefore, you will have to die.#Your pathetic attempts to make war have only caused us to have to move in to destroy you. We aren't particularly fond of the friend you are at war with, but we are fond of their money.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_ALIENSUCKUP_REJECT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Your gift is appreciated, but rejected.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We reject this gift.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Calculations indicate this gift is worthless. Offer rejected.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Your offer is kind, but I think we'll pass, [TheirLeaderName].#We appreciate the offer, [TheirLeaderName], but insist that you keep it for yourself.#We couldn't possible take this, [TheirLeaderName], but thank you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Thanks, but no thanks [TheirLeaderName].#I think we will pass on that, [TheirLeaderName].#Sorry [TheirLeaderName], we really don't need that.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>I think we can do without your 'gift', [TheirLeaderName].#Don't waste my time with such pathetic gifts, [TheirLeaderName].#No thanks, [TheirLeaderName]... I don't need your garbage.#I'll pass on your trash, [TheirLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_ALIENSUCKUP_ACCEPT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We accept your kind offer, [YourLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Offer accepted.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Offer accepted. Perhaps we will rethink your doom.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Thank you for the kind gift, [TheirLeaderName]!#The [YourEmpireName] is lucky to have such generous friends as you, [TheirLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Thanks for the gift, [TheirLeaderName].#We'll gladly take that, [TheirLeaderName].#The gift is appreciated, [TheirLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We'll gladly take accept your offer, [TheirLeaderName]... but in all honestly, we'll probably end up re-gifting it.#You sure know how to brown-nose, [TheirLeaderName].#The people of the [TheirLeaderName] sure know how to suck-up.#Well be taking that, [TheirLeaderName].#Perhaps your gift will keep your people alive a bit longer.#[TheirLeaderName], a bribe like this is always welcome.#Come bearing gifts, [TheirLeaderName]? Oh, how I love a good bribe...</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_ALIENWANTSPEACE_REJECT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>War will continue, fleshling.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Calculations indicate your forces are too weak to win this war, so I reject your peace treaty.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>I don't feel this peace treaty is the best option for my people. Destroying you, unfortunately, is the only way to bring true peace to the [TheirEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>No, I think the war will continue.#Peace will only come when you are destroyed.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>As much a we enjoy your pathetic begging, the war will not stop, and your empire will fall.#Why would we end a war when victory is in our grasp? No, [TheirLeaderName], your empire is doomed.#Don't you know that my troops only get more bloodthirsty when the prey shows weakness? Our forces will press forward, [TheirLeaderName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_ALIENWANTSPEACE_ACCEPT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Let us lay down our arms, [TheirLeaderName]. A brighter future awaits.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Yes, let us put this war behind us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>As much as we feel victory is in our grasp... we shall agree to this peace treaty.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="SURRENDER_TOPLAYER_PEACE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We are no longer capable of surviving as an independent power in the galaxy. We have decided to put our fate in your hands and surrender.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We realize now that we cannot possibly remain alive as an independent power. We have decided to surrender our forces to you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The atrocities we have committed will be paid back upon us ten-fold. Our only chance for survival is to surrender to you and hope that you can protect our people from retribution.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="SURRENDER_TO_OTHERPLAYER_PEACE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We have decided to surrender to the [SurrenderedTo]. We hope that they will have mercy and compassion for our people.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our war is lost. Before we are completely obliterated, we have decided that we shall surrender our remaining worlds to the [SurrenderedTo]. Our fate is in their hands.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The galaxy apparently doesn't want our particular brand of... enlightenment. Our military is crushed. Our economy is in ruins. We have decided that now is the time to surrender while we still can. The [SurrenderedTo] have made the best offer. Our worlds are now under their control.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="SURRENDER_TO_OTHERPLAYER_LONGWAR">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>You think you have won? You think you have beaten us? We shall deny you your final victory. We have decided to surrender to the [SurrenderedTo]. They will protect us from your wrath.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We curse you. While we know we cannot defeat you, we shall have the last laugh. We have surrendered to the [SurrenderedTo]!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You may have the upper hand. But, we shall deny you the spoils of war. The [SurrenderedTo] have offered to take our surrender and we have granted it. We shall meet again -- in hell!#You think you have beaten me? You think you have won! We shall thwart you yet, for we have decided to turn our worlds over to the [SurrenderedTo].#We hate you. You have ruined us. Our plans. Our dreams of conquest. But we shall escape you yet. We have chosen to give our worlds to the [SurrenderedTo]. We shall meet again!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="SURRENDER_TO_PLAYER_LONGWAR">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Drengin">1</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>You Humans have proven that you are powerful. We surrender.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are weary of this war and know it is un-winnable. We surrender.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We should have exterminated you Humans when we had the chance. You monkeylings have proven yourselves in battles this time. We surrender.#You Humans are a fraud. You claim to be the great diplomats and merchants of the galaxy. What a lie. Within your velvet glove is an iron fist. You Humans know warcraft far, far too well to be mere diplomats. War and fire come naturally to you. In the end, that fire and death that you bring to us today will be returned to you a 100 fold. We surrender.#You have utterly crushed us this time, Human. We surrender.#Your power is impressive. You Humans are not what you first appear to be. Behind your diplomatic facade you are cunning and brutal. We have no choice but to surrender.#You have utterly destroyed us. We have nothing left with which to fight you. We surrender.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>So the [SurrenderedTo] isn't so full of diplomatic niceties after all. You have won the war. We surrender.#We have nothing left with which to fight with. We surrender.#Please have mercy on us, we never wanted anything but friendship with the [SurrenderedTo]. We surrender.#Nothing seems to be able to stop you. We have no choice but to surrender.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are impressed with your power, Human. The galaxy may be yours eventually. For today, we hope you are satisfied with our worlds. We surrender.#You have defeated us. We offer you our surrender.#We cannot hope to defeat you so we surrender to you.#We offer our surrender to the powerful [SurrenderedTo]. You win.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Ah, the mask of the Humans is finally revealed for what it is. You are not diplomats or merchants. You are conquerors. The [SurrenderedTo] has won on this day but eventually others will rise against you.#So the [SurrenderedTo] are not what we thought they were. At first we dismissed you as being weak. It is now clear that you are cunning warriors. We surrender.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>You have defeated us. Our military is destroyed. Our population is in panic. You have won. We surrender.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The [SurrenderedTo] is too powerful for us. You have won. Please have mercy on us. We surrender.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We shall hate you forever, but you have won. You have utterly crushed our civilization. We bow to your power and strength and surrender ourselves to you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_SHIPNAMES">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Human">16</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Red Dog#Foxtrot#Maverick#FireBat#Eagle#Hawk Eye#Raptor</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>TAS Omega#TAS Hyperion#TAS Warlock#TAS Constitution#TAS Yorktown#TAS Iowa#Europa#TAS Tycho#Feistian#TAS Warsaw#TAS Berlin#TAS London#TAS Orion#TAS Cambridge#TAS Gibraltar#TAS Kalamzoo#TAS Plymouth#TAS Reagan#TAS Jacksonian#TAS Warlock</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>TAS Enterprise#TAS Reliant#TAS Dread Star#TAS Victory#TAS Justice#TAS Omega#TAS Overlord#TAS Vengeance#TAS Domination#TAS Invincible#TAS Britain#TAS Babylon#TAS Dreadnought</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Drengin">1</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Tas 'Rah#Kil-Hath#Zul#Rah-Kli#Klak 'Tir</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Kathos#Murgon#Zunra#Fatwath#Kinthir#Rin-tha</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Vath#Korg#Kona#Lotha#Domin#Alon#Zathox</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Yor">5</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>F-Thi#F-Na#F-Nir#F-Lax#F-Lon#F-Ken#F-Ala#F-Benth#F-Calan#F-Dormi#F-Ginao#F-Helo#F-Iolian#Zean#F-Zonan#F-Kav</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>M-Anth#M-Bana#M-Ceta#M-Detha#M-Epilosh#M-Trolo#M-Zima#M-Xith#M-Vox#M-Lordon#M-SapienDoom#M-Trolog#M-Kila</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>B-Ath#B-Calox#B-Domina#B-Jolo#B-Jolon#B-Katho#B-Lolo#B-Xoth#B-Xithar#B-Sifa#B-Trila</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Firehawk#Pain Sprout#Biter#Zinger#Bitey#Stinger#Zipper#Star Eagle#Falcon</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Warhawk#Battle Axe#Battle Hawk#Battle Hammer#Striker#Frigate#Destroyer#Cruiser</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Dominator#Dominion#Crusher#Battle Master#Aegis#Algenon#Death Stalker#Warlord#Battle Lord#Overlord#Zenon#Argon#Dominus#Triox#Cambrion</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Dreadlords">11</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Zith'ir</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Hith'Ox</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Gorgothox</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_DETECTS_PLAYER_THREAT_EASY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Stop. Just stop. You're embarrassing both of us. Let me guess, you are going to line up your invasion ships around our worlds and then, with a lightning strike, take out our defenses and then invade? Oh, you're a real strategic master. We are awed by your brilliance! You are lucky my generals are not set to "Intelligent" or higher or else I'd crush your ships like a bug. So please, have at it.#We can't help but notice that you've lined up some invasion ships around our planets. So let me guess, your previous military experience involves playing some sort of "video game" where you play only against computers and this tactic actually worked. You're not playing against some video game, we're sentient beings. Beings worthy of respect. However, you are fortunate in one way, my tactical generals intelligence is not "Intelligent" or better. So while I'm helpless to prevent what you are about to do, I wanted you to know that I know what you're about to do.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Stop. Just stop. You're embarrassing both of us. Let me guess, you are going to line up your invasion ships around our worlds and then, with a lightning strike, take out our defenses and then invade? Oh, you're a real strategic master. We are awed by your brilliance! You are lucky my generals are not set to "Intelligent" or higher or else I'd crush your ships like a bug. So please, have at it.#We can't help but notice that you've lined up some invasion ships around our planets. So let me guess, your previous military experience involves playing some sort of "video game" where you play only against computers and this tactic actually worked. You're not playing against some video game, we're sentient beings. Beings worthy of respect. However, you are fortunate in one way, my tactical generals intelligence is not "Intelligent" or better. So while I'm helpless to prevent what you are about to do, I wanted you to know that I know what you're about to do.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Look. You're just embarrassing both of us with this tactic. Surrounding our planets with Transports in preparation to attack? What do you think this is? A video game? If you were trying this tactic against a fellow being of your own kind would they just sit there and let it go unnoticed? Please. Fortunately for you, my military generals have been set to be too dumb to actually do anything about it. But I'm not. I see what you're doing. And if my generals had their intelligence at "Intelligent" or better, they'd squash you.#I'm insulted. Truly insulted. Putting a bunch of Transports right next to my worlds in preparation for attack? Real subtle. It's people like you that do this kind of thing against simple video games against the computer players on your planet. Then you go and tell others how the computer players are no match for playing other sentient beings and that is why "multiplayer" is a needed "feature". You're lucky my generals are too foolish to do something about it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_DETECTS_PLAYER_THREAT_INTELLIGENT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We can't help but noticed you've surrounded our planets with various Transports. Let me guess, you plan to attack and invade. Very creative. Rather than allow you to do that, we have decided to take preemptive action.#We're a kind and peaceful civilization. However, even we can't help but notice that you appear to be about to invade our worlds. In the interests of peace, we declare war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You apparently have us mistaken for some primitive computer-based game. We are sentient creatures and demand respect. Parking Transports around our world as you prepare to invade us is insulting to our intelligence. We are not going to wait for that invasion. We declare war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You pathetic creatures and your foolish strategies. Did you really think I would be blind to such an obvious attempt to invade our worlds? We shall destroy you before you destroy us. Prepare to die.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_COMPLAINS_SHIPTHREAT">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We are a virtuous civilization that values peace and justice. That said, we couldn't help but notice your significant military build up on our border. Would you mind removing those ships?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are not blind. We see the military build up. Remove your ships or we will do it for you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You dare put your ships right on our border? Remove them or we will remove them for you.#We do not appreciate having such a large military presence right near our worlds. Remove your ships.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_COMPLAINS_INFLUENCEBASE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Don't waste your time with Influencer starbases. We synthetic organisms are basically immune to your so-called culture.#Fleshling, your Influence starbase, [StarbaseName], is close to our worlds. We do not care for this. It is futile, however. We have no interest in your culture.#[StarbaseName] is trying to peddle influence on our civilization. Look at me closely, [OTHER_RACE_LEADER]. Do you really see me wearing clothing? Or eating your food? Think carefully.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Our people are really enjoying the new songs and fashions of your civilization. However, we are concerned that there may be too much of a presence of them. [StarbaseName] over in sector [X],[Y] is pretty far from your home planets. Some even argue that you are deliberately trying to influence our citizens. If you continue to do this kind of thing, it could affect our relations.#[StarbaseName]. Your starbase over in [X], [Y] is having quite a party. Some of our citizens are starting to be influenced by it even though it's closer to our worlds than it is to yours. You wouldn't be trying to culturally influence our people now would you?#Greetings, [OTHER_RACE_LEADER]. How you doing? Hey, you know, that Influencer starbase over in sector [X], [Y]? Yea, that one. Hey, it's a little closer to us than we'd like. Now, we're not saying you need to move it, but my military is starting to be concerned by this sort of thing.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You know, my daughter came back from a party the other day. A party over at [StarbaseName]. I didn't recognize that name. So I asked her about it, turns out it was a starbase that belongs to the [YourEmpireName]. I.e. YOU. Now, believe me, you do NOT want to see one of our kind wearing the clothes designed for your species (shivers). So we ask you to not build any more near us. I'll keep bringing this up as long as that starbase is there by the way.#I was going over my daily report from sector [X], [Y] and you're not going to believe what I heard. Yea, there's an Influencer starbase right there. I know, I couldn't believe it either. Look, we like our culture. So please remove that base or at least don't build anymore or else, well, bad things will happen -- to you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>[OTHER_RACE_LEADER]. Your Influencer starbase annoys us. The one over in sector [X], [Y]. Don't play coy. [StarbaseName] is a direct offense against our civilization. It's too close to our civilization. I will keep pestering you on this issue (or kill you depending on our military situation of course).#The [EmpireName] will not tolerate Influencer starbases parked around our civilization. Beware. Keep your Influencer starbases away from us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_COMPLAINS_MILITARYBASE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings, [OTHER_RACE_LEADER]. How you doing? Hey, wanted to bring up [StarbaseName]. The one located in sector [X], [Y]. Yea, I know those sector numbers aren't very helpful but, here's the thing, it's a military starbase. And well, I know you would never dream to build up a military base in order to attack us. But well, it is awfully close to our territory and your planets are ever so far away. So, could you get rid of it for the sake of our friendship?#You know, that military starbase you've got going near our planet is upsetting our military. Just a head's up.#You wouldn't be preparing to attack us would you? I mean, not us. We're all nice and friendly and peace loving. [StarbaseName] is making my commanders nervous.#My military commanders think you're preparing to attack us. Say it isn't so!#We don't want war with you. Consider your next moves carefully...</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>[OTHER_RACE_LEADER]. Your military starbase, a.k.a. [StarbaseName] is too close to our territory. If you value your relations with us, you'll remove it.#There's an ugly rumor going around that you are planning to attack us soon. Why would that be?#Sector [X], [Y] is claimed by us. Don't forget that.#Your military starbase is making us nervous. The one called [StarbaseName] (real creative name by the way).</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Look slaveling, or future slaveling, we don't appreciate your military starbase ([StarbaseName]) parked right near our territory. Stick them in your own area.#We're not fools, [OTHER_RACE_LEADER]. We know you're looking to attack us. You will regret underestimating us.#When you've been torturing and killing for as long as we have, you know what a surprise attack looks like. Spare us your novice build up strategy. Be careful where you put your forces, we're keeping an eye on you.#We don't care for your starbase layout, [OTHER_RACE_LEADER].#[OTHER_RACE_LEADER], let me be plain. Does the [YourEmpireName] want war with us? Because our sources tell us you are gearing up to attack.#The starbase called [StarbaseName] located in sector [X], [Y] is unacceptable to us. It constitutes an aggressive move on your part. Remove it or face the consequences.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="SURRENDER_TO_PLAYER_TEAM">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Yor">5</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Perhaps bioforms are stronger than synthetic forms of life. Our troops have been crushed and calculations indicate a slim chance of survival.Take our worlds... maybe you can make better us of them then we have.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>War has taken it's toll on my empire, [PlayerName]. My troops have fought, and died, at the hands of our enemies.  Now, I entrust our future to you. We surrender all our assets to the [SurrenderedTo].May they serve you well in this galactic struggle. Fare well, ally.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We've been defeated, [PlayerName]. Our forces fall as the enemy advances. We surrender all our worlds to you in hopes that, under your rule, they will survive this interstellar battle.Give 'em hell, [PlayerName]!#This war has broken my empire. Our economy is ruined, our forces are crushed, and the alliance between our nation and yours has withered. Luckily, your army is still strong enough to overcome the enemy. Take our worlds... use them to the best of your ability. May the glory of our nation live on through the powerful [SurrenderedTo].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="SURRENDER_TO_OTHERPLAYER_TEAM">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We lack the strength to survive this galactic war. Our worlds have been entrusted to the honorable [SurrenderedTo], who have been our friends throughout this conflict.May they overcome the evil that has terrorized the galaxy for so long.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We have succumbed to the powerful grasp of war, and will surrender to our allies, the [SurrenderedTo]. All our worlds now belong to them.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We have little power left to fight with. Our army is crushed, our economy is broken, and our research falls further behind. Perhaps our allies, the mighty [SurrenderedTo], will have more success in battle than we have. We hand our worlds over to them.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="DECLARE_WAR_TO_STOPAGGRESSION">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Human">16</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>On our planet, many years ago, a nation state called Germany nearly conquered the world because other nations stood by and watched them conquer weaker nations one by one. We recognize what you're doing and we won't stand by and allow this to happen on a galactic scale. We're coming for you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>On our planet, many years ago, a nation state called Germany nearly conquered the world because other nations stood by and watched them conquer weaker nations one by one. We recognize what you're doing and we won't stand by and allow this to happen on a galactic scale. We're coming for you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>On our planet, many years ago, a nation state called Germany nearly conquered the world because other nations stood by and watched them conquer weaker nations one by one. We recognize what you're doing and we won't stand by and allow this to happen on a galactic scale. We're coming for you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Your reign of terror is at an end. We will not permit you to roll over the galaxy one by one. Your war of aggression against the [FRIENDCIV] was unprovoked. #Your war with the [FRIENDCIV] has no merit. We will not stand by and watch you conquer the galaxy one civilization at a time. We declare war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Your war machine must be stopped. We declare war.#We will not tolerate your wars of aggression. We declare war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>As much as we admire your warlike ways, your war with our friends, [FRIENDCIV] has put us on notice that if we don't do something soon, we might be next.#Given your pattern of behavior, we realize that we might be next on the chopping block. So we've decided to go to war with you while we still can.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="DECLARE_WAR_PAIDOFF">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>It has recently been made economically justifiable to go to war with you.  Prepare to be destroyed.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We've been paid quite well to take care of you. So consider yourself taken care of. Prepare to die.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Certain..parties have provided us with funding to wipe you out.  Prepare to be destroyed.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_HELPSPLAYER">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We value your friendship and we believe that the [YOURENEMY] is a threat to stability in the galaxy. Therefore, we have decided to join the war on your side.#The [YOURENEMY] threatens us all. We have decided to join the war on your side.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The [YOURENEMY] must be stopped. So we have decided to come to your aid in this war.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Greetings, [YOURPLAYERNAME]. We have decided it is in our best interests to capitalize on the foolishness of the [YOURENEMY]. Therefore, we have joined the war against them.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_GOINGTOWAR">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We wanted to inform you that we have decided to go to war against the [AGGRESSORNAME]. Their brutal and unprovoked attack against the [DEFENDERSNAME] had to be responded to. Let this be a warning to all civilizations who would needlessly go to war.#We felt that we should inform you that the [DEFENDERSNAME] have been ruthlessly attacked by the [AGGRESSORNAME]. To stop such warmongering, we have decided to put together a force to deal with the [AGGRESSORNAME]. Feel free to join in.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The [DEFENDERSNAME] are under attack by the [AGGRESSORNAME].  In the name of galactic stability, we have decided to come to the aid of the [DEFENDERSNAME].  We felt we should allow you to be aware of this in case you wanted to join in.#The [DEFENDERSNAME] are the victims of a war of aggression by the [AGGRESSORNAME]. We have decided to intervene in the name of peace.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The [AGGRESSORNAME] are our kind of scum. The [DEFENDERSNAME] are weak and ripe for destruction. However, it is not in our interest that we let them go around conquering our food, err I mean our neighbors. So we have decided to take this opportunity to remove the [AGGRESSORNAME] from the galaxy. Feel free to join in the fun.#As much as we approve of the weak being wiped out, the [AGGRESSORNAME] are becoming too much of a threat. Their war with the [DEFENDERSNAME] is the perfect opportunity to deal with them.#The [AGGRESSORNAME] are beating us to the punch at wiping out weak civilizations such as the [DEFENDERSNAME]. But we cannot afford them to take over the entire galaxy so we have gone to war. You should join us in this task.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_PAIDOFF">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We wanted to inform you that we have decided to go to war against the [AGGRESSORNAME]. A power with a great deal of persuassion has encouraged us to do so.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The [AGGRESSORNAME] are not fit to survive. A third party that shall remain anonymous has made it clear that it is our duty to wipe them out.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The [AGGRESSORNAME] need to be wiped out. At least, that's what we've been paid to think. Either way, they will soon be destroyed.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_HUMAN_DECLARE_WAR">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>WAR is to be avoided at all costs, but now we have no choice#We have decided to punish the [TheirEmpireName] for its crimes against the universe.  Prepare for WAR!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Today, I declare that all [TheirEmpireName] worlds are only a mere province of the [YourEmpireName]. The use of force will ensure your compliance.#Let's see how tough the [TheirEmpireName] really is.  Prepare for WAR!</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Prepare your escape pods, [TheirLeaderName]! The [YourEmpireName] is coming for you!#Your time has come, [TheirLeaderName]! Prepare for WAR!#Your existence is a plague unto us all! The [TheirEmpireName] will be utterly destroyed!#I am appointing myself sovereign leader over all [TheirEmpireName] worlds.  Don't like it? Try and stop me!#Let the bloodshed begin!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_HUMAN_BREAK_ALLIANCE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Although we have appreciated the support of the [TheirEmpireName] as an ally, it is no longer necessary.#We thank the [TheirEmpireName] for its support as our ally, but it is time for an alliance to come to an end - peacefully.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>The alliance between [YourEmpireName] and [TheirEmpireName] is hereby dissolved.#The mighty [YourEmpireName] no longer requires the assistance of the [TheirEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>We thank the [TheirEmpireName] for supporting us in the past, but we no longer need your support.#Well, this has been a swell alliance, but things are different now.  Let's call it off.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="P_HUMAN_BREAK_SHARE_BONUS_TREATY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We no longer desire to share our resources with the [TheirEmpireName].  Is that alright?#The deal we made with the [TheirEmpireName] in the past has outgrown its usefulness. We would like to cancel it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We are no longer able to share with the [TheirEmpireName]. It's just too much for us.#We'd like to help you out, but we are no longer able to keep our agreement to share with the [TheirEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Remember when we decided to share? We were just joking.#We will no longer share our resources with the [TheirEmpireName].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BREAK_ALLIANCE_RESPONSE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Very well, we understand, but are a little disappointed.#We're sorry to see you go.#Is it something I said?</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>You're abandoning us?#If that's what you want...#Consider this alliance - dissolved.#Our alliance is nullified, [YourLeaderName], but I'd be lying if I told you I wasn't a bit surprised.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You're turning your backs on us, eh?#That's a shame.#Oh yeah? Who needs you, anyways?#Fine! I'll go start my own alliance with someone else who won't just get up and leave!</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_BREAK_SHARE_BONUS_RESPONSE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>This isn't making a good impression, [YourLeaderName].#You don't want to share with us anymore, eh? You're not making me very happy...</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Now THAT wasn't very nice...#You can't do that!  Well, I guess you just did, but still...</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>And you expect me to tolerate this?#Lesson 1 in Diplomacy 101: Do not take back something you share with someone else.  Paying attention, [YourLeaderName]?#Aw... I was just getting used to this whole 'Sharing' thing.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_NEGOTIATION_TREATYTOOEARLY">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Please don't take this the wrong way but we feel that it is too early for us to commit to any far reaching treaties at this time,</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>No. It's too early right now for us to get entangled in treaties.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You're kidding right? We have no idea whether your civilization is going to be worthy of our treaties. It's too early. Only if you prove your worth will we consider it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_NEGOTIATION_VALUABLETECH">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We are always interested in trading.  However, [Tech] is far too valuable for us to trade at this time. At least at any sort of reasonable price.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We must reject your offer. [Tech] is too important to our strategic goals to trade with someone else. We'd only trade it under the most favorable conditions.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Forget it. We worked very hard to get [Tech] and we have no intention to handing it over to anyone. You'd have to give...your right arm for it. For starters...</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_NEGOTIATION_VALUABLEPLANET_MAYBE">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>It is true that [Planet] isn't core to our civilization being far away from [Homeworld]. But it is still very valuable to us. You would need to compensate us.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>[Planet] is not crucial to our culture. But it is still a highly valuable world from our point of view. If you want it, you will have to pay for it.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>[Planet] is very far from [Homeworld]. So we might be willing to let you have it but only if you pay through the nose.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_NEGOTIATION_VALUABLEPLANET_NO">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>The planet [Planet] is crucial to our civilization's future. We are not willing to let it go.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>[Planet] is central to our culture now. It may seem like a trifle to you and indeed, you probably think we are unreasonable for caring about it, but we do.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>[Planet] is mine now. MINE. We shall do with it and its peoples as we please.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="AI_HELPSPLAYER_NOWAR">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>The unsteady foundations of peace have begun to falter, [YOURPLAYERNAME]. Reports from the [YOURENEMY] indicate [YOURENEMYLEADER] bares ill intentions towards the [YOURPLAYERCIV].
In keeping true the brotherhood between our nations, let my forces be the ones to strike down your opressive neighbor. Perhaps one day you can return the favor.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our scouts have picked up on military activity in [YOURENEMY] territory. Intelligence indicates that [YOURENEMYLEADER] plans a sneak attack on your worlds in the upcoming months, which would give your army little time to prepare, [YOURPLAYERNAME].
As a token of our friendship, let my army strike before the [YOURENEMY] does. We will eradicate [YOURENEMYLEADER] and make the galaxy safer for both our nations.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>The [YOURENEMY] agressions towards your nation have not gone overlooked, [YOURPLAYERNAME]. We will bare down on your opressor before [YOURENEMYLEADER] has a chance to strike.</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="HUMAN_WARALERT_NOWAR">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>We have taken pre-emtive action against the [AGGRESSORNAME], opressors of our friends in the [DEFENDERSNAME].
Bare agressions towards my friends and your worlds will suffer a similar fate, [YOURPLAYERNAME].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="WAR_ASCENSIONFEAR">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>We are normally a peace loving civilization. However, your pathway to ascension is a threat to our way of life. It is a threat we plan to eliminate by destroying you.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>While we do not have a general problem with your civilization, your control of so many ascension resources means that we have little choice but to destroy you before your civilization ascends.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>You pathetic fool. Did you really think we would stand by and allow you to simply ascend to the mastery of the galaxy?</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>
	<Topic Name="ANNOUNCE_RESEARCH">
		<Dialogue>
			<Speaker Name="Generic">10</Speaker>
			<Listener Name="Generic">10</Listener>
			<Phrase Morality="0">
				<Text>Greetings. We just wanted to inform you that we have just started researching [TECH]. Our technological advancements continue.#Our research program has continued to bring our civilization great triumphs. For instance, we have just begun researching [TECH].</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="1">
				<Text>Our mighty civilization is proud to announce that we have begun researching [TECH]. Tremble at our vast technology capability...#The technology you know of as [TECH] is will soon be understood by our civilization.#Hello there. We now have begun looking into [TECH]. Because of our long relationship, we are willing to give it to you. No, just kidding. We're not. Just teasing there. Yea, little bit cruel I know.#We will soon have [TECH]. Now, I'm not saying our civilization is more intelligent than your civilization. But on the other hand, I'm not saying we're not either.</Text>
			</Phrase>
			<Phrase Morality="2">
				<Text>Whohahah! We have just begun researching [TECH].#Grovel at our power and wisdom for we will soon have [TECH].#Now you know why evil will always triumph over good -- because good is dumb. Our civilization has just started researching [TECH].#Tremble in fear! Our offensively powerful and lethal civilization now has begun researching [TECH].#Cuddly creatures beware! For we will soon have [TECH].#Small furry animals walking on the roadside your doom is at hand for we are in the progress of obtaining [TECH].</Text>
			</Phrase>
		</Dialogue>
	</Topic>


</Topics>
